<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Quality3Ds Daily Pulse</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>Curated daily news for 3D printing enthusiasts.</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #33 - 2026-02-09</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 entX and University of Adelaide to scale nuclear battery production for space and defense
The University of Adelaide and South Australian nuclear technology company entX have secured funding to scale production of GenX, a betavoltaic nuclear battery designed for long-duration space and defense missions.
… The post entX and University of Adelaide to scale nuclear battery production for space and defense appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Adelaide_Uni_Additive_Manufacturing_sc_uv4ybm-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/entx-and-university-of-adelaide-to-scale-nuclear-battery-production-for-space-and-defense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 WASP completes Italy’s first certified 3D printed house using four robotic arms
Italian construction robotics company WASP has finished building Itaca, the country’s first certified 3D printed residential structure, using a four-arm robotic system at its Shamballa laboratory in Northern Italy.
The … The post WASP completes Italy’s first certified 3D printed house using four robotic arms appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/itaca-01-e1770596502206-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wasp-completes-italys-first-certified-3d-printed-house-using-four-robotic-arms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Hiroshima University team uses hot-wire laser method to 3D print industrial-grade WC-Co
Researchers at Hiroshima University have developed a new 3D printing method for tungsten carbide–cobalt (WC–Co) that prevents cracking and damage that often occur with laser powder bed and other melting … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 08, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1-s2.0-S0263436825005906-gr3_lrg-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/hiroshima-university-team-uses-hot-wire-laser-method-to-3d-print-industrial-grade-wc-co&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 SMRRF 2026, the UK’s biggest 3D print fest returns in one month
On March 7-8, 2026, the third edition of SMRRF (Sanjay Mortimer RepRap Festival) will take place at The Dalton Building at Manchester Metropolitan University.
The event brings together the 3D … The post SMRRF 2026, the UK’s biggest 3D print fest returns in one month appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/SMRFF-2024-e1770215840839-150x150.avif
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/smrrf-2026-the-uks-biggest-3d-print-fest-returns-in-one-month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Goldilocks’ Flywheel: Refractory Complex Concentrated Alloys (RCCAs) &amp;amp; The Race for the Future
Recently, Metalysis, Skyora, and Thermo-Calc Solutions started to try to commercialize Tanbium.
This alloy has been created for use in combustion chambers and rocket nozzles, reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 09, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/321691/goldilocksflywheel-refractory-complex-concentrated-alloys-rccas-the-race-for-the-future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 SmartBuild Brings Stereolithography to an Industrial Scale
While stereolithography is a well-established additive manufacturing technology used by many, it comes with its share of challenges, particularly when it comes to scaling up.
Manufacturers are often forced to make a difficult trade-off between speed and quality, while also…, reported by 3D Natives on Feb 08, 2026.
Image ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/02/Raplas_Smartbuild_cover.jpg
Read more ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/smartbuild-stereolithography-industrial-scale-09022026&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-33-2026-02-09</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #32 - 2026-02-08</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 H3X develops modular 3D printed 2-MW diesel genset system for marine and industrial markets
Using additive manufacturing, H3X is developing a modular 2-megawatt diesel generator set aimed at marine and industrial customers facing tighter space constraints and rising power density requirements.
The effort follows … The post H3X develops modular 3D printed 2-MW diesel genset system for marine and industrial markets appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/HEX_1770278381152-e1770377456844-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/h3x-develops-modular-3d-printed-2-mw-diesel-genset-system-for-marine-and-industrial-markets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 University of Maryland’s Extensive HVAC 3D Printing Program Signals a Turning Point
Goulding and Preeti Sulibhavi highlight how the University of Maryland’s extensive HVAC 3D printing program is moving additive manufacturing from experimental concepts to real-world energy infrastructure.
The post University of Maryland’s Extensive HVAC 3D Printing Program Signals a Turning Point appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/university-of-marylands-extensive-hvac-3d-printing-program-signals-a-turning-point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Adafruit Warns of Flaws in the New Firearm Screening Bills
3D printed firearms have become a growing concern for law enforcement in recent years.
Lawmakers and online platforms have introduced new restrictions targeting both the weapons themselves and the digital files used to produce them, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 07, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/STL-Preview-of-the-Urutau.-Image-via-the-Global-Network-on-Extremism-Technology-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/adafruit-warns-of-flaws-in-the-new-firearm-screening-bills-248769&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 US Air Force Base using on-site AM lab to overcome supply chain issues
The Warner Robins Air Logistics Complex at Robins Air Force Base, Georgia, is using additive manufacturing technology to sustain legacy aircraft and overcome supply chain problems that have made the … The post US Air...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 07, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/us-air-force-base-using-on-site-am-lab-to-overcome-supply-chain-issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 FlyingBear presents FFF printer with automatic plate changer on Kickstarter
An unusual accessory for FFF 3D printers has been presented on Kickstarter: FlyingBear is promoting APS, an automatic plate changer.
The system is designed to reduce downtime, reported by 3Printr on Feb 06, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/flyingbear-presents-fff-printer-with-automatic-plate-changer-on-kickstarter-1286713&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Anniversary Eyewear Blends Heritage with Advanced Manufacturing
Italian eyewear and sports gear company Rudy Project is celebrating 40 years of performance eyewear with the Performance 40, a limited-edition model that combines the brand’s 1985 design DNA with modern production...
Limited to 100 units worldwide and priced at €950, the frame features a lightweight titanium structure produced using 3D printing, allowing lattice […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-06-at-13.23.14-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/anniversary-eyewear-blends-heritage-with-advanced-manufacturing-248762&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 University of Dayton Secures $450K for CFAM Roadmap to Strengthen U.S. Defense Manufacturing
National additive manufacturing accelerator America Makes, in collaboration with the National Center for Defense Manufacturing and Machining (NCDMM), announced that the University of Dayton Research Institute has...
The effort is part of the Affordable and Agile Composite Additive Manufactured Structures […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/America-Makes-facility-face-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/university-of-dayton-secures-450k-for-cfam-roadmap-to-strengthen-u-s-defense-manufacturing-248753&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Building Beneath the Waves: Cornell Advances Underwater 3D Concrete Printing
An interdisciplinary team at Cornell University is developing a method to 3D print concrete directly underwater, aiming to enable faster, lower-impact construction and repair of critical subsea infrastructure such as...
Supported by the U.S, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/0128_printing2-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/building-beneath-the-waves-cornell-advances-underwater-3d-concrete-printing-248745&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-32-2026-02-08</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #31 - 2026-02-07</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Italian hospital scaling 3D surgical planning
A urological surgery team at IRCCS Ospedale Policlinico San Martino in Genoa, Italy, has fully integrated 3D surgical planning into routine clinical practice.
Nearly 300 kidney tumor reconstruction procedures have … The post Italian hospital scaling 3D surgical planning appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/materialise-mimics-augmented-reality-3d-planning-operation-room-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/italian-hospital-scaling-3d-surgical-planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Machina Labs Secures $124 Million at a Pivotal Moment for Defense Manufacturing
Machina Labs has raised $124 million in funding.
Investors include Woven Capital, Lockheed Martin Ventures, Balerion Space Ventures, and Strategic Development Fund (SDF), reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 06, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323727/machina-labs-raises-124-million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Barriers in Scaling and TPU Materials Limit Home Production of 3D Printed Footwear
The 3D print industry may be missing out on a major distributed application: footwear.
The post Barriers in Scaling and TPU Materials Limit Home Production of 3D Printed Footwear appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/barriers-in-scaling-and-tpu-materials-limit-home-production-of-3d-printed-footwear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Compact Pellet Extruder Enables High Content Feedstock Printing
A new research paper introduces a compact screw-based pellet extruder for high content feedstocks, and it could materially shift costs and throughput for polymer, metal and ceramic additive manufacturing.
The post Compact Pellet Extruder Enables High Content Feedstock Printing appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/compact-pellet-extruder-enables-high-content-feedstock-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Nodi releases innovative new DfAM features
Nodi, a node-based 3D modeling platform, has released a major update that introduces implicit modeling capabilities aimed at design for additive manufacturing (DfAM) workflows.
The new feature allows users to … The post Nodi releases innovative new DfAM features appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Bicycle-saddle-shape-created-with-Implicit-modeling-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nodi-releases-innovative-new-dfam-features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Slant 3D Proposes Catalog Platform as a Partial Solution to Widespread 3D Model Theft
3D model theft is rampant, and there’s not a lot that can be done.
The post Slant 3D Proposes Catalog Platform as a Partial Solution to Widespread 3D Model Theft appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/slant-3d-proposes-catalog-platform-as-a-partial-solution-to-widespread-3d-model-theft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 NASCAR turns to 3D printing to help USA Luge at the Winter Olympics
With the 2026 Winter Olympics kicking off in Italy this week, it was a surprise to no one at VoxelMatters that there would be some great 3D printing stories emerging.
… The post NASCAR turns to 3D printing to help USA Luge at the Winter Olympics appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/milano-cortina-1-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nascar-3d-printing-usa-luge-winter-olympics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Behind the Scenes of Netflix’s Stranger Things: 3D Printing in Action
3D printing is transforming visual effects by converting digital designs into tangible, highly detailed props with higher speed and precision.
For filmmakers, this allows complex scenes to be executed safely, efficiently, and with greater creative flexibility, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stranger-things-2-780x470.jpg-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/behind-the-scenes-of-netflixs-stranger-things-3d-printing-in-action-248756&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-31-2026-02-07</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #30 - 2026-02-06</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 AnyShape marks milestone with 200 3D printed titanium implants in past year
AnyShape, an industrial additive technologies company, has applied its expertise in cutting-edge aerospace innovation to successfully help more than 200 medical patients regain mobility in the past year.
The company’s … The post AnyShape marks milestone with 200 3D printed titanium implants in past year appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/AnyShape-implant-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/anyshape-marks-milestone-with-200-3d-printed-titanium-implants-in-past-year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Bambu Lab’s Creator Protection Program Takes Down 200+ Unauthorized 3D Models
Bambu Lab has launched a new program to protect creators’ content.
The post Bambu Lab’s Creator Protection Program Takes Down 200+ Unauthorized 3D Models appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/bambu-labs-creator-protection-program-takes-down-200-unauthorized-3d-models&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Australian city to use carpet waste for 3D printed city infrastructure
Geelong city council has tasked Deakin University and local carpet and flooring manufacturer Godfrey Hirst with exploring a solution to convert carpet manufacturing waste into feedstock for 3D printing.
The … The post Australian city to use carpet waste for 3D printed city infrastructure appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Geelong-bollards-01-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/australian-city-to-use-carpet-waste-for-3d-printed-city-infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Recycled, custom-fit, 3D-printed: Lululemon builds flagships with a new design playbook
Lululemon is opening two new flagship stores in SoHo (New York) and Gangnam (Seoul), showcasing a new store concept: more movement, community, and sensory experiences.
Recycled, partly 3D-printed materials, terrazzo, wood details, and an immersive light installation are intended to make the visit feel like a journey while also referencing the brand’s roots in the […] The post, reported by 3Printr on Feb 05, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/recycled-custom-fit-3d-printed-lululemon-builds-flagships-with-a-new-design-playbook-2086674&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Optofluidic assembly method enables 3D microstructures from metals, oxides, and quantum dots
Researchers from the Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems, ETH Zurich, KTH Royal Institute of Technology, the National University of Singapore, and Koç University have developed an optofluidic 3D...
Reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 05, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-2-e1770282769904-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/optofluidic-assembly-method-enables-3d-microstructures-from-metals-oxides-and-quantum-dots-248729&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Food 3D Printing Enters New Territory With Patent for Plant-Based Salmon Replication
An unusual patent describes a method to 3D print plant-based salmon sashimi.
The post Food 3D Printing Enters New Territory With Patent for Plant-Based Salmon Replication appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/food-3d-printing-enters-new-territory-with-patent-for-plant-based-salmon-replication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 0rCA’s containerized recycling unit turns marine waste into PA6
Based out of Cornwall, England, OrCA was founded by a team of engineers, designers, and sustainability experts that saw first-hand the effects of marine waste on coastal environments and wanted … The post 0rCA’s...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 05, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/longships-pellets.jpg-2-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/orca-containerized-recycling-unit-turns-marine-waste-pa6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Formnext 2026 names the United Kingdom as partner country
The upcoming Formnext 2026 will feature the United Kingdom as its partner country, highlighting a robust additive manufacturing ecosystem spanning systems, software, and industrial applications.
Established players such as Renishaw … The post Formnext 2026 names the United Kingdom as partner country appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Crowded-aisles-at-Formnext-2025.-Copyright-Formnext-Mesago-Messe-Frankfurt-Mathias-Kutt-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/formnext-2026-names-the-united-kingdom-as-partner-country&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-30-2026-02-06</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #29 - 2026-02-05</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Nivalon Leverages AI and 3D Printing to Create Personalized, Motion-Preserving Spinal Implants
company creating patient-specific spinal implants Nivalon Medical Technologies has developed what it describes as the first fully patient-specific spinal implant that preserves natural motion without metal components.
The device combines AI-driven design with advanced ceramic 3D printing, using a zirconia-toughened alumina (ZTA) structure and a flexible core to replicate spinal movement, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 03, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Youngstown_Business_Incubator_Device_image-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/nivalon-leverages-ai-and-3d-printing-to-create-personalized-motion-preserving-spinal-implants-248657&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 US startup Variloom develops 3D printed clothes process to minimize waste
Variloom, a Palo Alto-based startup in the fashion textile space, is developing what it claims is a “transformative filament and 3D printing system designed for ultra-efficient fabrication of versatile and … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 04, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Variloom-YKK-zipper-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/us-startup-variloom-develops-3d-printed-clothes-process-to-minimize-waste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Metal 3D printing on Mars: shielding gas from the atmosphere instead of argon
For longer missions on Mars, metal 3D printing will become important as a tool for repair and infrastructure.
A preprint study (arXiv) tested three shielding-gas environments when selectively laser melting 316L stainless steel: argon, CO₂, and air, reported by 3Printr on Feb 04, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/metal-3d-printing-on-mars-shielding-gas-from-the-atmosphere-instead-of-argon-4986652&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Sustaining Autonomous Warfare: On-Site Production and Training in the U.S. Army
Army is actively modernizing how it maintains autonomous and semi-autonomous systems on the battlefield.
Drawing lessons from the Russia-Ukraine conflict, the Army is deploying mobile 3D printing and machining units, training soldiers in advanced manufacturing, and experimenting with in-field recycling of materials to, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 04, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/original-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/sustaining-autonomous-warfare-on-site-production-and-training-in-the-u-s-army-248684&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 YouTuber measures breaking forces: Toolpath tuning noticeably changes FDM strength
By default, many slicers first print the outer walls of FDM parts and then add the infill to the component.
Maker NeedItMakeIt investigated a potential weak point in this sequence and tested an alternative line layout, reported by 3Printr on Feb 04, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/youtuber-measures-breaking-forces-toolpath-tuning-noticeably-changes-fdm-strength-5286666&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 New York Proposal to Regulate 3D Printers Could Disrupt Manufacturing, Hobbyist, and Industrial Use
It looks like New York State is now contemplating new laws for 3D printers that could cripple the technology in that state.
The post New York Proposal to Regulate 3D Printers Could Disrupt Manufacturing, Hobbyist, and Industrial Use appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/new-york-proposal-to-regulate-3d-printers-could-disrupt-manufacturing-hobbyist-and-industrial-use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Lululemon rolls out 3D printed storefronts and interiors globally
Lululemon has integrated a custom 3D printed ceiling and storefront system into key retail locations worldwide, including Milan and New York’s SoHo neighborhood, with Birmingham and Tokyo to follow.
The … The post Lululemon rolls out 3D printed storefronts and interiors globally appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Aectual-04-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/lululemon-rolls-out-3d-printed-storefronts-and-interiors-globally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📷 OTEC optimizes automated finishing for 3D-printed earmolds and titanium ear pieces
Custom earmolds (otoplastics) are now often produced via additive manufacturing because geometries from an ear scan can be manufactured directly as one-off parts.
However, a downside of common 3D-printing processes remains the typical surface roughness of the raw parts, reported by 3Printr on Feb 04, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/otec-optimizes-automated-finishing-for-3d-printed-earmolds-and-titanium-ear-pieces-5186654&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-29-2026-02-05</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #28 - 2026-02-04</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 In situ bioink mixing during 3D bioprinting is now a possibility
Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have developed a magnetically actuated mixing platform called MagMix that integrates directly into standard extrusion 3D bioprinters.
The solution addresses a long-standing … The post In situ bioink mixing during 3D bioprinting is now a possibility appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Printer-01-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/in-situ-bioink-mixing-during-3d-bioprinting-is-now-a-possibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Stratasys launches qualification program for SAF PA12 nylon material
The qualification of SAF PA12 is being conducted through the NCAMP materials qualification process.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 03, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/STRP048-Image-H350-fleet.JPG
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/stratasys-launches-qualification-program-for-saf-pa12-nylon-material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Study Finds Common Home 3D Printing Ventilation Methods Insufficient to Control Emissions
A new study raises significant concerns about home 3D printing safety.
The post Study Finds Common Home 3D Printing Ventilation Methods Insufficient to Control Emissions appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/study-finds-common-home-3d-printing-ventilation-methods-insufficient-to-control-emissions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Work with recycled plastic and 3D-printed molds
Additive manufacturing has established itself in recent years as a tool for prototypes and small series.
However, as soon as large quantities of small plastic parts with consistent dimensional accuracy are required, 3D printing reaches its economic limits, reported by 3Printr on Feb 03, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/work-with-recycled-plastic-and-3d-printed-molds-1486618&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Mercedes-Benz and Siemens join consortium for AM produced electric motors
Paderborn University has initiated a three-year research project aimed at producing electric motor components through additive manufacturing, with the goal of delivering production-ready e-motors that are lighter,...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 03, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/AddRemo-team-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/mercedes-benz-and-siemens-join-consortium-for-am-produced-electric-motors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Purge Calibration is a Key Method to Reduce Filament Waste in Multicolor 3D Printing
Have you heard of “purge calibration”?
The post Purge Calibration is a Key Method to Reduce Filament Waste in Multicolor 3D Printing appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/purge-calibration-is-a-key-method-to-reduce-filament-waste-in-multicolor-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Stranger Things’ season 5 VFX included 3D printed body doubles
The final season of Netflix’s hit show Stranger Things was nothing short of a media phenomenon, with people organizing elaborate watch parties and tons of anticipation over the fate of the … The post Stranger Things’...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 03, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stranger-things-2-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/stranger-things-season-5-vfx-included-3d-printed-body-doubles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Metal 3D Printing Firm VulcanForms Brings Total Funding to $575M With New Investment
VulcanForms has raised a very large investment.
The post Metal 3D Printing Firm VulcanForms Brings Total Funding to $575M With New Investment appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/metal-3d-printing-firm-vulcanforms-brings-total-funding-to-575m-with-new-investment&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-28-2026-02-04</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #27 - 2026-02-03</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 CRAFT controls crystallinity during 3D printing and varies hardness and transparency pixel by pixel
Researchers at the University of Texas at Austin and Sandia National Laboratories present CRAFT, a 3D-printing process that controls material properties at pixel-level resolution via grayscale light.
Using just a single cyclooctene-based resin, a DLP/LCD printer can create hard, opaque regions and soft, transparent regions—such as for realistic hand models for surgical training or shock-absorbing […] The post, reported by 3Printr on Feb 02, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/craft-controls-crystallinity-during-3d-printing-and-varies-hardness-and-transparency-pixel-by-pixel-0886603&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Passoni’s new Omni OT-01 bike combines 3D printed and machined titanium
The adoption of additive manufacturing in the cycling world has been increasing in recent years, with high-performance bike makers leveraging various versions of the technology to engineer more lightweight,...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 02, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/passoni-bike-2-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/passoni-new-omni-ot-01-bike-integrates-3d-printed-titanium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Underwater 3D Concrete Printing Breakthrough Could Transform Ocean and Maritime Construction
A team from Cornell has successfully 3D printed concrete — underwater.
The post Underwater 3D Concrete Printing Breakthrough Could Transform Ocean and Maritime Construction appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/underwater-3d-concrete-printing-breakthrough-could-transform-ocean-and-maritime-construction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Rosatom to lead implementation of 3D metal printing in Kyrgyzstan’s hydropower sector
Rosatom, the Russian State Agency for Atomic Energy, has signed an agreement to implement additive technologies in Kyrgyzstan’s hydropower sector, the corporation has stated.
Signed in the Kyrgyz capital Bishkek, … The post Rosatom to lead implementation of 3D metal printing in Kyrgyzstan’s hydropower sector appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Kyrgyzstan-AM-agreement-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/rosatom-to-lead-implementation-of-3d-metal-printing-in-kyrgyzstans-hydropower-sector&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Platform Auto-Replacing System for 3D Printers Draws Little Interest
There’s a very curious 3D print Kickstarter running now, FlyingBear APS.
The post Platform Auto-Replacing System for 3D Printers Draws Little Interest appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/platform-auto-replacing-system-for-3d-printers-draws-little-interest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Nordic Alpha Partners secures significant minority stake in Additive Drives
The German company is a manufacturer of high-performance 3D printed electric motor technology.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 02, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/hairpin-stator-2.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/nordic-alpha-partners-secures-significant-minority-stake-in-additive-drives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 VulcanForms raises additional $220m in oversubscribed round
It follows a previous financing round in which the company raised more than $350m.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 02, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/VulcanForms-production-closeup-1.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/vulcanforms-raises-additional-220m-in-oversubscribed-round&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 ACMI purchases multiple EOS metal additive manufacturing platforms
The organisation's investment in metal AM includes the world's first deployment of an AMCM M 8K.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 02, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/ef560bd1-d69f-4795-b1a5-3638c4041d9f.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/acmi-purchases-multiple-eos-metal-additive-manufacturing-platforms&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-27-2026-02-03</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #26 - 2026-02-02</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🏠 Cornell team advances underwater 3D printing of concrete project
A team of interdisciplinary researchers at Cornell University is making significant progress in a bid to successfully 3D print concrete underwater, in response to a project call from the Defense Advanced … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 01, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Cornell-underwater-3D-concrete-printing-04-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/cornell-team-advances-underwater-3d-printing-of-concrete-project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Why Industrial 3D Printing Is More Than a Machine Decision: An Interview with Marina Schreiner of 3D-WERK
3D-WERK Black Forest GmbH, based in St.
Georgen in Germany’s Black Forest region, positions itself as a provider of industrial additive manufacturing with a clear focus on practical implementation in production environments, reported by 3Printr on Feb 02, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/why-industrial-3d-printing-is-more-than-a-machine-decision-an-interview-with-marina-schreiner-of-3d-werk-2786454&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 #239 NexusAM CTO Sebastian Larsen on enabling 'better functionality &amp;amp; economics' with in-situ monitoring
NexusAM is in the process of developing an AI-powered in-situ monitoring capability for metal additive manufacturing.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 02, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/01/Additive-Insight-Re-Design--16-.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/podcasts/239-nexusam-cto-sebastian-larsen-on-enabling-better-functionality-economics-with-in-situ-monitoring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 ORNL Develops Novel Extrusion System for Single-Stream, Multi-Material 3D Printing
We’ve been talking a lot about multi-material printing lately, and for good reason.
The technology is advancing rapidly on both the maker and professional sides, from Bambu Lab’s and Prusa’s latest multi-material desktop systems to more experimental approaches, reported by 3D Natives on Feb 01, 2026.
Image ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/multimaterial-3d-printing.jpg
Read more ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/ornl-multi-material-prints-02022026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Who’s The Biggest In 3D Printing, February 1, 2026
Once again we take a look at the valuations of the major 3D printing companies over the past week.
The post Who’s The Biggest In 3D Printing, February 1, 2026 appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/whos-the-biggest-in-3d-printing-february-1-2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Iris van Herpen’s Dreamlike Designs Are Coming to Brooklyn Museum
Starting May 16, 2026, the Brooklyn Museum will host the North American debut of Iris van Herpen‘s Sculpting the Senses, a major exhibition that brings together more than 140 of the designer’s...
Reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 01, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323614/iris-van-herpens-dreamlike-designs-are-coming-to-brooklyn-museum&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-26-2026-02-02</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #25 - 2026-02-01</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Nivalon Medical produces metal-free spinal implant using advanced ceramic printing
Nivalon Medical Technologies, an innovative spinal healthcare company, claims to have successfully produced the world’s first fully patient-specific, motion-preserving spinal implant built entirely without metal.
Using XJet’s NanoParticle Jetting ceramic … The post Nivalon Medical produces metal-free spinal implant using advanced ceramic printing appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Nivalon-02-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nivalon-medical-produces-metal-free-spinal-implant-using-advanced-ceramic-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Engineering Meets Culinary Art with Columbia’s 3D Printed Three-Course Meal
Nimra Shakoor and Charles R.
Goulding take readers inside Columbia’s six-year experiment that turned quiche, pizza, and pie into a laser-cooked showcase of how 3D printing could redefine the future of food, reported by Fabbaloo on Jan 31, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/engineering-meets-culinary-art-with-columbias-3d-printed-three-course-meal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Is This U.S. Start-Up Really Building the World’s Fastest Metal 3D Printer? - All3DP
Is This U.S.
Start-Up Really Building the World’s Fastest Metal 3D Printer, reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 31, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOMjNmaFhyMEVXeGNVQWFwSXpITXdsYXdCZXpOUlVURFZ6WUcxOXRkS19zT0ZfcnJoWWtlZUxHR0puM1M4VWdXSEpKV05BV0NKWTBLU0JvQmIydzlibkp0cXBjUi1VREgxUTF3UHN0NFZfNUdmU2tnTmJHV192X2tXTlczaTFyaS1LNkFQSWJvMWExWDZOR01DZDln?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Looking Back – Feb. 1 - The Republic News
Looking Back – Feb.
1 The Republic News, reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Feb 01, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibEFVX3lxTE53NFdublQ5WTZibk84UGtGbkhmRlJnLWJGZmQ4UkFiWDZ2MkNWTlVXMUNSbXBVTk5RaHF6QVdLLVJwQ3lwTHlNN0F4ZUh2cXJDZnNUZFQ5bThvTklWb3g1R3duTkt2cGNzeUVLYg?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Changing Print Layer Patterns To Increase Strength - Hackaday
Changing Print Layer Patterns To Increase Strength Hackaday
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Feb 01, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNWGd4a004d3lXeGliRHpTQkUxV3lPYzIxODZGUXNrbDFuQXJfZEVuYlJkRVQ5QWJFMEJETk5aaFlFQ0ZXMWZndU9NY2JEZnVTQkQ1a0lMTUc2emdaZDY1eUFrbzVKUmVJb0xRQ2t0ekJlWmpyazYyM1RfLTBCc09SWUtzNVNhekt4TS1j?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 The internet keeps telling you to 3D print these—don’t - How-To Geek
The internet keeps telling you to 3D print these—don’t How-To Geek
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 31, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPT2hNRGNZNmJRZFJ1Q3hlZEc2ckRlTC1iR0UwUlpHR0xfZEhFU3lMYWtEYnh4Z2N1eDd5ZkNyaE5ncy16NEpsYUExS2lhSVZlNnhCNmtWd2dRMFhvZlhjcE01MVo3N3VpbGlfM1JKZ3FaX1dMMmNPZ1drS2Ywdm9XbWdpS284SFE?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Feature: Here's All The Best Switch 2 &amp;amp; Nintendo Stuff I've 3D Printed So Far - Nintendo Life
Feature: Here's All The Best Switch 2 &amp;amp; Nintendo Stuff I've 3D Printed So Far Nintendo Life
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 31, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxNYUVHaUxMM0Z1cllfV3ZqZ01COXRvU3BCUFVTdENTNW9HT2hSTVpUME94WFNQZXFYTFlPN1Z1dUZFMnpCSjJ0WWlMWHdEWmZHNnl0YXhpSmNpREg2bnlHZ3JDRTIzWDhBd3Znb3lnRGZPTDNRSGsxM0ItWkpOeml4Z1EwM3RPOFA2YVh1RGFJTnJYaGw0eFRMbEppNVZkaXZXMExCV0FpWm8ydw?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 VulcanForms to scale further following $220m funding round
VulcanForms, a leading metal additive manufacturing solution provider, has closed a significant $220m funding round in what it says reflects “growing demand for secure domestic production of next-generation metal...
… The post VulcanForms to scale further following $220m funding round appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/VulcanForms-Command-Center-scaled-e1769850195457-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/vulcanforms-to-scale-further-following-220m-funding-round&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-25-2026-02-01</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #24 - 2026-01-31</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Nivalon Creates a Custom, Metal-Free Spinal Implant Using XJet 3D Printing
Nivalon Medical Technologies says it has successfully produced a fully patient-specific spinal implant that preserves motion and contains no metal, using AI-based design and ceramic 3D printing.
The implant is, reported by 3DPrint.com on Jan 30, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323596/nivalon-creates-a-custom-metal-free-spinal-implant-using-xjet-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Bambu Studio v2.5 adds remote AMS drying controls and new slicer tools
Bambu Lab’s latest Bambu Studio update focuses on device control and print-quality refinements for multi-material jobs.
Release notes cite remote AMS drying control for AMS 2 Pro/AMS HT on H2D plus prime-tower tweaks for PLA/PETG mixing and support-interface ironing, released Jan 27, 2026.
Read more ? https://github.com/bambulab/BambuStudio/releases/tag/v02.05.00.65&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Underwater 3D printing may reshape maritime concrete construction - Tech Xplore
Underwater 3D printing may reshape maritime concrete construction Tech Xplore
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 29, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNZTU1NVNLYm50NG56VE4xQjNfWlg4VU1ERkVQRHk5ZzV6cTJTOWwzUmV2YTlTWmNrZ1RHeVF5OEZNZ3ZEeDczT0Q5OV9nc2lSN19waHY5bThMQjJVVWlBelliSmMzaklxSWktTHBQV2dQS3htczJTMmpXZFBjcVJIa3JCdTZYVTA?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 3D-printed mold as casting mold: YouTuber makes plaster cast
Many casts from 3D-printed parts are made using silicone molds.
Many people do this not only with metal, but also with plaster or chocolate, reported by 3Printr on Jan 30, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/3d-printed-mold-as-casting-mold-youtuber-makes-plaster-cast-3286586&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 3D Printing Health and Safety - Toronto Metropolitan University
3D Printing Health and Safety Toronto Metropolitan University
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 30, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQUzhUVS1VM0ZGeUsyYmxYcFROdEFKRVFEcnFadnpzVXV5dE10Q2oxOWJtaHNCRXhNYTV0cF9NSU9GTF9MV194cUxqMG9LeXRubFpiQjR1OTNXVHVuNVJsOHdGZFkwMTF1dnc3akc3ZzR1SlJSVG1kMmljMEJzR21KSnR3VVByZktRQUYyR1ByUzBBZ2tHRnZZck5lTU5rR3NYT3lFWFozY3o2NVRoTVhjQVBTcFpaQmZSSUYxbkQ4ME5ta0hOX2lRXw?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Creality teases closed-loop filament recycling with Shredder R1 and Filament Maker M1
Creality previewed a two-machine workflow that shreds failed prints into small particles and extrudes them back into usable filament.
The company says the system targets a closed-loop setup for home shops and plans to launch via crowdfunding, with pricing not yet announced.
Image ? https://hackster.imgix.net/uploads/attachments/1924842/image_KyKXuqsBQu.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;w=830&amp;amp;h=466.875&amp;amp;fit=min&amp;amp;dpr=1.25
Read more ? https://www.hackster.io/news/creality-promises-a-closed-loop-filament-workflow-with-the-shredder-r1-and-filament-maker-m1-341ac48e749d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Prusa Cuts Prusa XL Price as Multicolor 3D Printing Competition Intensifies
Prusa Research has lowered their price for the tool-changing Prusa XL 3D printer.
The post Prusa Cuts Prusa XL Price as Multicolor 3D Printing Competition Intensifies appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/prusa-cuts-prusa-xl-price-as-multicolor-3d-printing-competition-intensifies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 UT Austin researchers achieve complex human hand 3D print with single material
Researchers at the University of Texas at Austin have developed a 3D printing method that can create complex replicas – like human hands – with varying hardness, from a single … The post UT Austin researchers achieve...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Jan 30, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/CRAFT-3D-printing-method-e1769786297828-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/ut-austin-researchers-achieve-complex-human-hand-3d-print-with-single-material&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-24-2026-01-31</guid></item></channel></rss>