<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Quality3Ds Daily Pulse</title>
    <link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link>
    <description>Curated daily news for 3D printing enthusiasts.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>3D PRINTING PULSE #19 - 2026-01-26</title>
      <link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 AZORG integrates PrintPlace directly onto healthcare workfloors
AZORG is structurally embedding 3D printing within its hospital by establishing PrintPlace on the Moorselbaan campus.
This brings product development, prototyping, and small- to medium-scale production directly onto healthcare workfloors, reported by VoxelMatters on Jan 25, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/KIR08845-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/azorg-integrates-printplace-directly-onto-healthcare-workfloors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 3D Printing Innovations in Acute Maxillofacial Trauma Care - BIOENGINEER.ORG
3D Printing Innovations in Acute Maxillofacial Trauma Care BIOENGINEER.ORG
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 25, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxQanAzR1lqS1lNWW1lUGFNaHlMN3NhbWR0eGZKYjMxSGtPUWlmSElwdlZqS2ZBN1hkMC01djhjX1ZlRUZ1OTdoUFJTRFNKdEhUQ0ZWUHl2eThJcjlOc3ZwenFEMXZ2b2Y3OGVHYWo3UUNJdWJQWHR3Ul9sV1J5UDFoamVNd2t2ak9hOVQ0?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 5 Countries Just 3D-Printed Homes in Under a Week: The Future Is Here - Yanko Design
5 Countries Just 3D-Printed Homes in Under a Week: The Future Is Here Yanko Design
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 24, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOYl96TmpRbHhpd19jV1B0RExIandDRlVxdTU1bzBmQ2FTU1dYbHdSX2lGNzVYRjlNVFdnRW9oeHcxMjFpNlJ5QlBJamNLTTB6cFczWHVUN2hUa21Ea1UwYTU5X1pWRUxITEs4MHN2YzBEM2tGa0c4S3hvQUYzclQ0bmlWODZ1b1ZNc3RiT2RFMlFuV0R3cXhxV0wxektkZHpnZ1VGNE9mQ0loT1pu0gGyAUFVX3lxTFA4a1Q4cFNPeTlrMkVxcXVyZzA4LXVtb05oRlZTSFBwZG5nWFNkOHNDNmpYM1c3amF2N3d5THRwOU9xNnBrMzlOSS1yWE81ZGRMMWo1blBUOEVwcnFaUzVoNVFsOG1uRUxwOFBuLTNqeXVYTk12Y3JkN0NFbkV6Skgtd0JUSWIxMG5HeDlzOFAzZEhMYmprV3BjTTgteWc0WXl1RHluUTNKdjNNMXdxYUhvM1E?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 New Nitrides for Mass Production: The C1000 FLEXMATIC Reaches an Industrial Milestone
Ceramic additive manufacturing is no longer limited to prototyping and is gradually establishing itself as an industrial production solution.
Designed to meet stringent performance and reliability requirements, today’s ceramic AM processes now leverage advanced materials suited for demanding environments, reported by 3D Natives on Jan 25, 2026.
Image ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/01/3DCeram_cover.jpg
Read more ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/nitrides-c1000-flexmatic-industrial-milestone-26012026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 China conducts first metal 3D printing experiment in space - Qazinform
China conducts first metal 3D printing experiment in space Qazinform
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 25, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQZWFpSE9aRjE4Z3J3TUxwUklmR3lHM3Jncml3N0w0bkdhODhpS3pzbWJNd2RYWmVlVVgteEYwc0hFQzJfT0RhZHJWVkJaWlpUV0tiVGZXWUhCZ2FSN3lLMExHaldsbnc1Q1FpX0x5R2I3LUhVUm5yM3J5bHllWUpzTkpacmVMbnltemJmUDhsSnA0cWYtWXRV0gGXAUFVX3lxTE9CV1NEMHd5QlJkbmc3b1BFbW5yTmowYVRwWEkzc2RUaUFDRVo0Q3o5SGs3T1NwbEVCbmpqVkxGeHJ4SEtOMFhJLU0wOFFZUTd6U0pBRXBOaktwOGdtRXJlS3prMFlsdFg1c1dDNlFRMDBkZ3FjWlNsNmt0OEhGN25pdDg0R3ZFTGxpVTAtaWlMN2o1TWRjdU0?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Creative Fabrica Enters the Third Dimension: New AI Tools Turn Text into 3D Print Models Instantly - savannahnow.com
Creative Fabrica Enters the Third Dimension: New AI Tools Turn Text into 3D Print Models Instantly savannahnow.com
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 25, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNNzd0VzY2RE5fVVVDbDk5U3ZYbVVERDBfUGdIdnBKWWlfNmsxczZwb1dPblNIQkR0QkxTTHR1SFN2bm9WYnpVcWRkU2JEZGdjdjVsdTNNZk9vM1NFUGtkM0czR0duaGJHTVRPQmpVUFRHWEhGTUs2RS1rU1VIRzNhNjRVek9jbGFabjZGaFBDSUJRTUNDT0hJMEROcEYyN1VhZXF2NWgwbjZlOExaLURFMUxuLUdYTmRfRjBxS1l2YWVvUW5XVnVhRldENGFsZHNkdjlKczRYYkhaU29CdzRZNjdrLWpaRVk?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Nottingham University 3D prints surfaces for quantum sensors
According to Nottingham University, scientists have created 3D printed surfaces featuring intricate textures that can be used to bounce unwanted gas particles away from quantum sensors, allowing useful particles like...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Jan 25, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/printedsurfaces.xee28e267-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nottingham-university-3d-prints-surfaces-for-quantum-sensors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 3D Printing: Transforming Psoriasis Treatment and Diagnosis - BIOENGINEER.ORG
3D Printing: Transforming Psoriasis Treatment and Diagnosis BIOENGINEER.ORG
Reported by Google News - 3D Printing on Jan 25, 2026.
Read more ? https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNUXdiRDhLc1BmbDVIYklaUnUzVnFUbG04S2g1UWdjWVg5RnVvcVA1VndVdXlCdF9zaXdka3puc3V3Ynl6XzhRSkZxaURndmZZaGc1cWJLVXRMb3VzZGFmZ09XRU9kanhVUHRfUERpS3VJY3dkTUJwMTd3bHMxRjlud1hHMkZyNjdPQzNN?oc=5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>pulse-19-2026-01-26</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D PRINTING PULSE #18 - 2026-01-25</title>
      <link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🖨️ ORNL researchers combine multiple 3D printing extruders
Oak Ridge National Laboratory researchers are exploring multi-extruder setups to expand material and process capability in a single build.
Reported by VoxelMatters on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/ornl-researchers-combine-multiple-3d-printing-extruders/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨️ Conveyor-Belt 3D Printing for Series Production: Layerloop Industrializes an Alternative FFF Concept
Layerloop is pushing conveyor-belt style printing as a path to serial production and continuous builds.
Reported by 3Printr on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/conveyor-belt-3d-printing-for-series-production-layerloop-industrializes-an-alternative-fff-concept-2286427/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧬 Partnership Brings Digital 3D Printing for Orthotics and Prosthetics to Mexico
A new partnership aims to expand access to digital fabrication for orthotics and prosthetics in Mexico.
Reported by 3Printr on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/partnership-brings-digital-3d-printing-for-orthotics-and-prosthetics-to-mexico-2186426/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧪 Laser Parameters Control Material Properties: New Insights into Metal 3D Printing
New findings highlight how laser parameters influence material properties in metal additive manufacturing.
Reported by 3Printr on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/laser-parameters-control-material-properties-new-insights-into-metal-3d-printing-2786422/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 3D Printing with Recycled Titanium: IperionX Produces Prototypes for U.S. Military Vehicles
IperionX is producing recycled-titanium prototypes for U.S. military vehicles using additive manufacturing.
Reported by 3Printr on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/3d-printing-with-recycled-titanium-iperionx-produces-prototypes-for-u-s-military-vehicles-1786428/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧪 Optical data fiber in filament: Kai Parthy outlines concept for standard hot ends
A proposed filament concept would carry optical data fiber while remaining compatible with standard hot ends.
Reported by 3Printr on Jan 23, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/optical-data-fiber-in-filament-kai-parthy-outlines-concept-for-standard-hot-ends-1486451/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>pulse-18-2026-01-25</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D PRINTING PULSE #17 - 2026-01-24</title>
      <link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🫁🧬 VR + 3D Printing Could Help Repair Lungs (Not Replace Them)
Researchers are combining virtual reality planning with 3D printing to explore new ways to bridge damaged lung sections.
The RI-MUHC team in Montreal is using VR lung models to plan 3D-printed hollow connectors that could link healthy tissue to bypass damaged areas (reported Jan 8, 2026).
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/muhc-researchers-test-vr-and-3d-printing-for-better-lung-repair-247926/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀🛠️ Rocket Lab Shows Why 3D-Printed Engines Are Here to Stay
Additive manufacturing is still a core advantage for faster rocket iteration and production.
Rocket Lab's Rutherford engine relies heavily on metal 3D-printed components, highlighted during a Jan 13, 2026 visit covered by VoxelMatters.
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/secretary-hegseth-visits-rocket-lab-and-divergent/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠🏗️ 3D-Printed Homes: ICON's "Printed Neighborhood" Playbook Goes Mainstream
3D-printed housing is shifting from novelty builds to repeatable community construction.
Fine Homebuilding reports ICON is building 12 new 3D-printed homes in Austin, Texas, using gantry printers to create structural walls with built-in cavities for utilities (published Jan 12, 2026).
Read more ? https://www.finehomebuilding.com/2026/01/12/printed-houses-are-here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨️🌈 Bambu Lab Watch: H2C Is "On the Way" (Multi-Tool Ambitions Continue)
Bambu is openly teasing what's next in its H-series ecosystem, signaling more capability ahead.
In a company blog update dated Jan 7, 2026, Bambu Lab discusses the H2C roadmap and the business tradeoffs of announcing it alongside existing H-series models.
Read more ? https://blog.bambulab.com/h2c-is-on-the-way-heres-how-it-all-started/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📷🔍 3D Scanners: Creality's "Sermoon P1" Goes Standalone at CES 2026
Creality is pushing scanning toward grab-and-go workflows without needing a laptop tether.
The Sermoon P1 was shown at CES 2026 as an all-in-one 3D scanner with an integrated computer, display, and battery (posted Jan 10, 2026).
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/creality-unveiled-its-new-sermoon-p1-all-in-one-3d-scanner-at-ces-2026-1086140/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤖🩻 AM Software Breakthrough: AI Reads X-Ray Print Data Faster for Better Metal Parts
Quality control is getting a speed boost as AI starts "watching" metal prints more intelligently.
UCL researchers introduced AM-SegNet to rapidly process X-ray images captured during metal AM, aiming to improve reliability for demanding applications (published Jan 13, 2026).
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/ucl-team-develops-ai-tool-to-monitor-metal-additive-manufacturing-248041/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🧠🤖 Multi-Material Printing Expands Horizons with AtomForm Palette 300
At CES 2026, AtomForm's Palette 300 impressed with 12 nozzles capable of mixing 36 colors and 12 materials.
The system points toward richer multi-material workflows for creative and functional prints (coverage by Android Authority).
Read more ? https://www.androidauthority.com/atomform-palette-300-3d-printer-3630645/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📡📈 Industry Forecast: Metal AM Moves Toward True Production Scale
Across aerospace and defense and beyond, experts see industrial metal additive manufacturing shifting from prototype to production.
Analysts expect certified hardware and materials to rise in use as companies expand full-scale metal AM output in 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/322917/3d-printing-predictions-2026-industrial-production-in-metal-additive-manufacturing/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>pulse-17-2026-01-24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D PRINTING PULSE #7 - 2026-01-14</title>
      <link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;?? Bambu Lab Awarded Patent for Intelligent Speed Adjustment
Bambu Lab continues to innovate with a new patent for an intelligent speed-adjusting method.
This technology aims to automatically enhance print quality by adjusting parameters in real-time based on print conditions.
Read more ? https://fabbaloo.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?? Kelowna Cancer Centre Personalizes Radiation with 3D Printing
Medical professionals in Kelowna are leveraging 3D printing to improve patient outcomes.
The centre is using custom 3D-printed boluses to precisely personalize radiation therapy for cancer patients.
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?? U.S. NDAA 2026 Targets Additive Manufacturing Supply Chain
The latest National Defense Authorization Act introduces new restrictions on 3D printing systems for defense.
The act focuses on securing the supply chain by limiting procurement of systems tied to specific foreign entities.
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?? 3D Printed Rammed Earth: A New Era for Sustainable Housing
Large-scale construction is looking to the past to build the future with rammed earth 3D printing.
This technique combines one of humanity's oldest building materials with modern robotics for sustainable architecture.
Read more ? https://fabbaloo.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?? Bambu Lab A1 Printers Empower Prosthetic Production in Guatemala
Brent Wright and the LifeEnabled foundation are bringing low-cost prosthetics to those in need.
Utilizing a fleet of Bambu A1 printers, the team is producing functional prosthetic feet directly in the field.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?? MUHC Researchers Combine VR and 3D Printing for Lung Repair
Innovations in respiratory medicine are seeing the fusion of virtual reality and additive manufacturing.
Researchers are testing these technologies to create more accurate models for complex lung repair procedures.
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>pulse-7-2026-01-14</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
