<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Quality3Ds Daily Pulse</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>Curated daily news for 3D printing enthusiasts.</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #40 - 2026-02-16</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Lululemon SoHo Store Installs Large-Format 3D Printed Benches by Decibel Built
Shoppers visiting the new Lululemon flagship store in SoHo might notice something new and original when they sit down.
The benches inside the space were not carved from wood or, reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 15, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323922/3d-printed-benches-bring-sustainable-design-to-lululemons-new-soho-flagship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Researchers develop a 3D printing ink that recycles with water
Researchers at the Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon’s Institute of Functional Materials for Sustainability in Teltow, Germany, have created a water-based 3D printing ink composed of approximately 70% lignin, a byproduct of...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 15, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Recycled-printing-ink-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/researchers-develop-a-3d-printing-ink-that-recycles-with-water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Fast and precise microdevice production enabled by sound-driven 3D printing
Researchers at Concordia University have developed a 3D printing technique that uses focused ultrasound to fabricate microscale structures on soft polymers, with a precision up to 10 times finer than … The post Fast...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 15, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/41378_2025_1035_Fig1_HTML-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/fast-and-precise-microdevice-production-enabled-by-sound-driven-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Make Good leverages 3D printing to offer real-world accessibility
Modern technologies, often associated with expensive gadgets and industry, are also having a growing social impact.
One example of this approach is the nonprofit organization Make Good, which uses 3D … The post Make Good leverages 3D printing to offer real-world accessibility appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MakeGood-08-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/make-good-leverages-3d-printing-to-offer-real-world-accessibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 There’s Always Room for 3D Printed Batteries
There are many applications where you have limits on how much you can cram into a particular space.
There are also many applications where you need as much battery as …read more, reported by Hackaday 3D Printing on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/pdw.png
Read more ? https://hackaday.com/2026/02/14/theres-always-room-for-3d-printed-batteries&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-40-2026-02-16</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #39 - 2026-02-15</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Researchers develop degradation-triggered 4D printed actuators for biomedical applications
Researchers from the Universidad Politécnica de Madrid and the IMDEA Materials Institute, in collaboration with German medical technology company Meotec, have developed a degradation-triggered 4D printing method that...
Published in Additive Manufacturing, the study shows that hydrolytic degradation of polyvinyl alcohol (PVA) can be […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-9-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/researchers-develop-degradation-triggered-4d-printed-actuators-for-biomedical-applications-248900&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Hypersonix sets launch window for 3D printed engine-propelled hypersonic craft
Pioneering Brisbane-based aerospace startup Hypersonix Launch Systems has scheduled a late February launch window for a test flight of its DART AE, a 3.5-meter scramjet-powered hypersonic aircraft that’s designed to...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Hypersonix-01-e1770978909521-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/hypersonix-sets-launch-window-for-3d-printed-engine-propelled-hypersonic-craft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Housing Affordability, Innovation and 3D Printing
Goulding and Preeti Sulibhavi analyze how companies like Pulte, Lennar, D.R.
Horton, and KB Home are integrating additive manufacturing to cut costs and boost energy efficiency, reported by Fabbaloo on Feb 14, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/housing-affordability-innovation-and-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 The 3D printed rotor guards tested, raced and won at the highest level of mountain biking
Disc brake covers have become a regular sight on the professional downhill MTB scene, and a UK-based company – G10 PRJCT – has brought the tech to the public at … The post The 3D printed rotor guards tested, raced...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSCF8760-1-e1771026458953-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/the-3d-printed-rotor-guards-tested-raced-and-won-at-the-highest-level-of-mountain-biking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Chinese team 3D print millimeter-scale objects in under one second
Researchers at Tsinghua University in Beijing have developed a 3D printing method that is able to fabricate complex millimeter-scale objects in 0.6 seconds – a feat the team has claimed … The post Chinese team 3D...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DISH-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/chinese-team-3d-print-millimeter-scale-objects-in-under-one-second&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Thingiverse Joins MyMiniFactory in Major 3D Printing Community Consolidation
MyMiniFactory, a curated 3D printing community where independent designers and brands sell digital models, has completed the full acquisition of Thingiverse from Netherlands-based 3D printer manufacturer Ultimaker.
The move brings over eight million users into MyMiniFactory’s ecosystem and incorporates Thingiverse into its SoulCrafted platform, which emphasizes human-created designs, curated collections, and sustainable, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/019c4cb5-826f-70bf-9bff-4bd98ac52b36-cover-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/thingiverse-joins-myminifactory-in-major-3d-printing-community-consolidation-248924&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Dutch additive manufacturing software group Dimanex declared bankrupt
Small but influential digital supply chain startup collapses amid tightening capital and slower enterprise adoption A Dutch software company that sought to transform industrial supply chains through additive...
Dimanex B.V., a Utrecht-based developer of […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCI-MacBook-Frame-1-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/dutch-additive-manufacturing-software-group-dimanex-declared-bankrupt-248922&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 3DPI Executive Survey 2026: The Future of 3D Printing and The Year of Institutional Filters
The additive manufacturing industry has spent two decades arguing about what’s possible.
In 2026, the conversation has finally shifted to what’s survivable, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/State-of-Investment-Series-1-1-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/3dpi-executive-survey-2026-the-future-of-3d-printing-and-the-year-of-institutional-filters-248919&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-39-2026-02-15</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #38 - 2026-02-14</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 MIT researchers give further insight into 3D bioprinting mixer
Researchers at MIT who developed a magnetic mixing device that solves a fundamental challenge in 3D bioprinting have spoken about MagMix and its potential future impact on regenerative medicine.
The … The post MIT researchers give further insight into 3D bioprinting mixer appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MagMix-01-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/mit-researchers-give-further-insight-into-3d-bioprinting-mixer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Exploring additive manufacturing in the 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations
The newly released 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations introduce significant updates concerning additive manufacturing (AM), reflecting the evolving role of this technology in motorsport engineering.
These regulations establish the materials, … The post Exploring additive manufacturing in the 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/FIA-2026-Formula-1-regulations-3-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/exploring-additive-manufacturing-in-the-2026-formula-1-technical-regulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Japan's first government-approved two-story 3D printed reinforced concrete house completed
The 537-square-foot house is said to meet Japan’s stringent seismic design requirements.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/image--12--1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/japans-first-government-approved-two-story-3d-printed-reinforced-concrete-house-completed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ AM Solutions introduces upgraded M1 surface finishing system for 3D printed metal &amp;amp; polymer parts
The new M1 combines smoothing, grinding, polishing, and deburring in a single vibratory finishing platform.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/M1--1--1.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/am-solutions-m1-surface-finishing-metal-polymer-parts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 Five use cases that show the life-changing impact of medical 3D printing
This month, our AM Focus is shining a light on the medical sector, where additive manufacturing technologies have not only been broadly adopted but have gained notable mainstream attention (admittedly … The post Five...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/osorio-spinal-implant-02-082825-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/five-use-cases-that-show-the-life-changing-impact-of-medical-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 PrintBio joins federal kidney bioprinting program
PrintBio, a New York City-based regenerative medicine and bioprinting company, has joined a multidisciplinary research consortium that’s being funded by the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H) – a …...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/PrintBio-01-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/printbio-joins-federal-kidney-bioprinting-program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Leitat and DISCMAM help shape AM Village 2026 program across Madrid and Albacete
Leitat Technological Center joined the second preparation meeting for AM Village 2026 in Madrid, represented by Xavier Tutó, where organizers refined the technical and operational plan for the five-day workshop … The...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/WAAM3D_AM-VILLAGE-2026-Meeting-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/leitat-and-discmam-help-shape-am-village-2026-program-across-madrid-and-albacete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 [INTERVIEW] Thingiverse Reboot Targets Creator Pay Tools and Tighter AI Controls after MyMiniFactory Acquisition
Thingiverse, one of the oldest and most visited libraries of downloadable 3D-print files, is being repositioned around creator monetisation, human-led curation and stricter handling of AI-generated uploads after its...
Romain Kidd, the newly appointed chief executive of Thingiverse and former MMF CEO, said the platform remains large by any consumer internet […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/019c4cb5-826f-70bf-9bff-4bd98ac52b36-cover-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/interview-thingiverse-reboot-targets-creator-pay-tools-and-tighter-ai-controls-after-myminifactory-acquisition-248928&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-38-2026-02-14</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #37 - 2026-02-13</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 restor3d launches Ossera AFX ankle fusion cage system
restor3d, a global leader in patient-specific, 3D printed, musculoskeletal implants, has launched its Ossera AFX Ankle Fusion Cage System for full commercial distribution, in an expansion of the platform that … The...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ossera-AFX-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/restor3d-launches-ossera-afx-ankle-fusion-cage-system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 British aerospace firm Orbex set to enter administration
The Exploration Company is among those to have explored an acquisition of the company.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/380A1599_2022-05-27-131523_hkda-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/orbex-set-to-enter-administration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Two-story 3D printed home passes Japan’s stringent seismic standards
As a country that experiences upwards of 500,000 earthquakes every year, Japan is correct to have highly stringent building requirements.
These requirements—the New Anti-seismic Structure Standard from 1981 in particular— … The post Two-story 3D printed home passes Japan’s stringent seismic standards appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/cobod-japan-1-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/two-story-3d-printed-home-seismic-approval-japan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Application spotlight: 100-micron 3D printed veneers enable reduction in teeth grinding for patients
BMF believes it is the world's thinnest veneer product.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/01/image-61-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/application-spotlight-100-micron-3d-printed-veneers-enable-reduction-in-teeth-grinding-for-patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 MyMiniFactory acquires Thingiverse from Ultimaker
MyMiniFactory has acquired 100% of Thingiverse from Ultimaker, bringing together nearly 8 million users under a single platform that has paid out over $100 million to independent creators since its … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MyMiniFactory-Thingiverse-merger-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/myminifactory-acquires-thingiverse-from-ultimaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 ARKKY’s next-gen 3D printed shoes blend design, innovation, and sustainability
ARKKY is a young footwear brand with a modern approach to fashion.
The company emphasizes that it does not follow patterns or trends but sets them itself, reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ARKKY-01-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/arkkys-next-gen-3d-printed-shoes-blend-design-innovation-and-sustainability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Researchers investigate turning construction waste into metal 3D printing feedstock
BMWE-funded research project explores if CO₂ emissions from construction sector could be significantly reduced using recycled steel to build reusable 3D printed facade brackets.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Image1_AddMamba-scaled.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/researchers-investigate-turning-construction-waste-into-metal-3d-printing-feedstock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Ceramitec puts additive manufacturing of technical ceramics on center stage
The conference program at the Ceramitec 2026 trade fair in Munich, from March 24 to 26, will foreground additive manufacturing, with multiple sessions on 3D printed technical ceramics and digitally … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ceramitec-Konferenzprogramm-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/ceramitec-puts-additive-manufacturing-of-technical-ceramics-on-center-stage&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-37-2026-02-13</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #36 - 2026-02-12</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Composite AM startup Perseus Materials backed by defense giant
Perseus Materials, a young company that is promising to transform large-scale composite part production with its resin-based technology, has just received a strategic investment from American defense and aerospace...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 11, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/perseus-lockheed-1-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/composite-am-startup-perseus-materials-lockheed-martin-funding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 First Certified 3D Printed Home in Italy Built for Self-Sufficiency
WASP’s construction-focused startup WASP 3D Build has completed the 3D printing of the walls for Itaca, a self-sufficient home billed as Italy’s first certified 3D printed construction.
Located at the Shamballa open air laboratory in the hills of Northern Italy, the structure complies with Italian and European construction regulations, including earthquake resistance standards, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 11, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/260113_3D_printing_of_Itaca_self-sufficient_farm_4K-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/first-certified-3d-printed-home-in-italy-built-for-self-sufficiency-248825&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Blended Material Transitions In Large Format AM Studied
Researchers mapped how material composition changes during switchovers in large format, pellet-fed 3D printing.
The post Blended Material Transitions In Large Format AM Studied appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/blended-material-transitions-in-large-format-am-studied&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 WAAM3D expands global footprint with deals in the US and Malaysia
WAAM3D and National Aerospace Industry Corporation Malaysia have signed a memorandum of understanding at the Singapore Airshow to establish wire arc additive manufacturing capabilities at the MyAERO Centre.
NAICO positions … The post WAAM3D expands global footprint with deals in the US and Malaysia appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/WAAM3D_6971fea28564dd09b5f6fe66_WAAM-System-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/waam3d-epxands-global-footprint-with-deals-in-the-us-and-malaysia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 British Army advancing 3D printed drone capabilities
The British Army manufactured and deployed first-person view (FPV) attack drones in field conditions during Exercise Bull Storm in Kenya last summer, marking what officers described as a probable first … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 11, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/British-Army-drones-02-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/british-army-advancing-3d-printed-drone-capabilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 MakerWorld launches Creator Copyright Protection Program
MakerWorld has launched a new program to help protect creators’ intellectual property and remove links that redirect users to sites where stolen projects can be purchased.
This applies to the … The post MakerWorld launches Creator Copyright Protection Program appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MW-01-150x150.png
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/makerworld-launches-creator-copyright-protection-program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 US Army GVSC qualifies Velo3D to support AM integration into Defense Industrial Base supply chain
Velo3D is said to have met all GVSC qualification criteria in less than two weeks.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 11, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Velo-3D-Sapphire-C_Original-1024x683.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/us-army-gvsc-qualifies-velo3d-to-support-am-integration-into-defense-industrial-base-supply-chain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Harvard Harnesses Multimaterial 3D Printing to Build Programmable Soft Robots
Predictable motion in soft robotics has traditionally depended on complex molds and multi-step fabrication processes, slowing design iteration and limiting customization.
Researchers at Harvard University have now introduced a multimaterial 3D printing approach that embeds actuation directly into flexible structures during fabrication, allowing soft robotic devices to be produced with, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 11, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/fig_5_rotational_3D_printing-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/harvard-harnesses-multimaterial-3d-printing-to-build-programmable-soft-robots-248843&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-36-2026-02-12</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #35 - 2026-02-11</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 3D printed synthetic brain models developed by Mizzou team replicate tissue complexities
A team at the University of Missouri’s College of Engineering has built 3D printed models of the human brain that mimic the mechanical, thermal, and dielectric properties of real tissue.
… The post 3D printed synthetic brain models developed by Mizzou team replicate tissue complexities appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/20251205_NIT_ENG-3D-Brain-019-Show-Me-Mizzou-Hero-Image-2000x1333-1-e1770738669830-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/3d-printed-synthetic-brain-models-developed-by-mizzou-team-replicate-tissue-complexities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 restor3d's 3D printing-enabled Ossera AFX Ankle Fusion Cage System now commercially available
Prior to commercial launch, restor3d conducted a successful limited market release of Ossera products over the past several months.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/1740_3_4_front-1-1536x864.png.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/restor3ds-3d-printing-enabled-ossera-afx-ankle-fusion-cage-system-now-commercially-available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Protecting 3D Printing Designs: MakerWorld Introduces Creator Copyright Program
As 3D printing grows in popularity, creators increasingly face unauthorized copying and sales of their designs.
Digital platform and community for 3D printing creators MakerWorld’s new Creator Copyright Protection Program addresses this problem, providing procedural support, streamlined reporting, and international enforcement, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 09, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/01-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/protecting-3d-printing-designs-makerworld-introduces-creator-copyright-program-248798&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 Osteopore continues Asia expansion drive with Singapore 3D printing service line
Osteopore, a company specializing in 3D printed biomimetic and bioresorbable implants for craniofacial reconstruction, rhinoplasty, orthopedic, and dental surgery, is set to continue its growth in Asia with the...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Osteopore-02-e1770719763114-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/osteopore-continues-asia-expansion-drive-with-singapore-3d-printing-service-line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Researchers develop degradable 4D printed actuators using PETG and PVA
A team of researchers from the Universidad Politécnica de Madrid and IMDEA Materials Institute has developed a method for creating shape-changing devices through controlled material degradation, which opens up the …...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/IMDEA-01-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/researchers-develop-degradable-4d-printed-actuators-using-petg-and-pva&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Hawk Ridge Systems now offering Stratasys PolyJet, SLA &amp;amp; DLP 3D printing technologies
The companies believe their partnership will support the development of advanced prototyping, tooling and end-use manufacturing applications across several sectors.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Untitled-design--14-.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/hawk-ridge-systems-now-offering-stratasys-polyjet-sla-dlp-3d-printing-technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Solving LPBF Inconel 718 Distortion: ASTRO and FSU Announce 2026 3D Printing Tech Challenge
Florida State University’s InSPIRE Institute and the Applied Science &amp;amp; Technology Research Organization of America (ASTRO America) have announced the second national 3D Printing Tech Challenge.
The 2026 challenge addresses a major constraint in precision additive manufacturing for aerospace and defense: predicting and compensating in LPBF Inconel 718, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1770221610371-150x100.jpeg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/solving-lpbf-inconel-718-distortion-astro-and-fsu-announce-2026-3d-printing-tech-challenge-248802&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 The Sanjay Mortimer RepRap Festival Returns to Manchester in 2026
The Sanjay Mortimer RepRap Festival (SMRRF) is back in Manchester on 7–8 March 2026, uniting makers, engineers, students, and industry players for two days of immersive workshops, hands-on demonstrations, robotics...
Organised by the Sanjay Mortimer Foundation in partnership with PrintCity, SMRRF 2026 will feature a […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 10, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1768413440231-150x100.jpeg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/the-sanjay-mortimer-reprap-festival-returns-to-manchester-in-2026-248809&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-35-2026-02-11</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #34 - 2026-02-10</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Harvard researchers push further with 3D printing method for programmable soft robots
Researchers at Harvard’s John A.
Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences have taken a developing 3D printing technique that produces soft robots with predictable, programmable movements and encoded movement … The post Harvard researchers, reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 09, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Robot-hand-01-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/harvard-researchers-push-further-with-3d-printing-method-for-programmable-soft-robots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Russia prepares proposal for experimental 3D printing in construction
Russia’s State Duma Committee on Economic Policy has prepared a proposal to establish an experimental legal regime for 3D printing in construction, Russian newspaper Vedomosti has reported.
The business daily … The post Russia prepares proposal for experimental 3D printing in construction appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CyBe_Betonindustrie-Brievengat_BiB_Curacao_Caribbean_construction_3D_Close-up-printing-copy-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/russia-prepares-proposal-for-experimental-3d-printing-in-construction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Penn State researchers create 4D printed hydrogel that conceals and displays images on demand
A team of researchers at Penn State University has developed a 4D printing technique for programmable hydrogel films that hide and reveal embedded images in response to environmental triggers, with … The post Penn...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 09, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4D-hydrogel-Mona-Lisa-scaled-e1770650606930-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/penn-state-researchers-create-4d-printed-hydrogel-that-conceals-and-displays-images-on-demand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 3D printing restores decapitated Robert Louis Stevenson statue
A new exhibition at the University of Leeds’ Treasures of the Brotherton gallery is putting the spotlight on the art of portrait busts.
The exhibition, called Who am I to you?, … The post 3D printing restores decapitated Robert Louis Stevenson statue appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/rls-leeds-3-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/3d-printing-restores-decapitated-robert-louis-stevenson-statue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 How the Durable Project uses AM to redesign fusion reactor wall components
DURABLE is a research project focused on using additive manufacturing to redesign the plasma-facing components (PFCs) of fusion reactors.
The work aims to leverage optimized geometries, internal cooling channels, and … The post How the Durable Project uses AM to redesign fusion reactor wall components appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Interior-of-the-Alcator-C-Mod-tokamak-at-the-MIT-Plasma-Science-and-Fusion-Center-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/how-the-durable-project-uses-am-to-redesign-fusion-reactor-wall-components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 VoxelMatters Composites AM Focus 2026 eBook
We are kicking off our 2026 eBook series with our Composites AM focus.
This vertical, which we have watched both closely and eagerly over the years, is a versatile one … The post VoxelMatters Composites AM Focus 2026 eBook appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Composites-AM-2026-eBook-Feature-Image-150x150.png
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/voxelmatters-composites-am-focus-2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Elementum 3D brings 6061 and 2024 aluminum into L-PBF using reactive in-situ ceramics
Elementum 3D is extending LPBF to legacy high-strength aluminum grades by synthesizing ceramic reinforcements during printing.
The company’s reactive additive manufacturing, or RAM, mixes heat-producing materials into the feedstock so … The post Elementum 3D brings 6061 and 2024 aluminum into L-PBF using reactive in-situ ceramics appeared, reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 09, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/elementum3D-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/elementum-3d-brings-6061-and-2024-aluminum-into-l-pbf-using-reactive-in-situ-ceramics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 AM Ceramics 2026
The conference will host the world’s ceramic 3D printing experts.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 09, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/AMC24-303-scaled.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/events/am-ceramics-2026&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-34-2026-02-10</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #33 - 2026-02-09</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 entX and University of Adelaide to scale nuclear battery production for space and defense
The University of Adelaide and South Australian nuclear technology company entX have secured funding to scale production of GenX, a betavoltaic nuclear battery designed for long-duration space and defense missions.
… The post entX and University of Adelaide to scale nuclear battery production for space and defense appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Adelaide_Uni_Additive_Manufacturing_sc_uv4ybm-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/entx-and-university-of-adelaide-to-scale-nuclear-battery-production-for-space-and-defense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 WASP completes Italy’s first certified 3D printed house using four robotic arms
Italian construction robotics company WASP has finished building Itaca, the country’s first certified 3D printed residential structure, using a four-arm robotic system at its Shamballa laboratory in Northern Italy.
The … The post WASP completes Italy’s first certified 3D printed house using four robotic arms appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/itaca-01-e1770596502206-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wasp-completes-italys-first-certified-3d-printed-house-using-four-robotic-arms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Hiroshima University team uses hot-wire laser method to 3D print industrial-grade WC-Co
Researchers at Hiroshima University have developed a new 3D printing method for tungsten carbide–cobalt (WC–Co) that prevents cracking and damage that often occur with laser powder bed and other melting … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 08, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1-s2.0-S0263436825005906-gr3_lrg-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/hiroshima-university-team-uses-hot-wire-laser-method-to-3d-print-industrial-grade-wc-co&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 SMRRF 2026, the UK’s biggest 3D print fest returns in one month
On March 7-8, 2026, the third edition of SMRRF (Sanjay Mortimer RepRap Festival) will take place at The Dalton Building at Manchester Metropolitan University.
The event brings together the 3D … The post SMRRF 2026, the UK’s biggest 3D print fest returns in one month appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/SMRFF-2024-e1770215840839-150x150.avif
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/smrrf-2026-the-uks-biggest-3d-print-fest-returns-in-one-month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Goldilocks’ Flywheel: Refractory Complex Concentrated Alloys (RCCAs) &amp;amp; The Race for the Future
Recently, Metalysis, Skyora, and Thermo-Calc Solutions started to try to commercialize Tanbium.
This alloy has been created for use in combustion chambers and rocket nozzles, reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 09, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/321691/goldilocksflywheel-refractory-complex-concentrated-alloys-rccas-the-race-for-the-future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 SmartBuild Brings Stereolithography to an Industrial Scale
While stereolithography is a well-established additive manufacturing technology used by many, it comes with its share of challenges, particularly when it comes to scaling up.
Manufacturers are often forced to make a difficult trade-off between speed and quality, while also…, reported by 3D Natives on Feb 08, 2026.
Image ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2026/02/Raplas_Smartbuild_cover.jpg
Read more ? https://www.3dnatives.com/en/smartbuild-stereolithography-industrial-scale-09022026&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-33-2026-02-09</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #32 - 2026-02-08</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 H3X develops modular 3D printed 2-MW diesel genset system for marine and industrial markets
Using additive manufacturing, H3X is developing a modular 2-megawatt diesel generator set aimed at marine and industrial customers facing tighter space constraints and rising power density requirements.
The effort follows … The post H3X develops modular 3D printed 2-MW diesel genset system for marine and industrial markets appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/HEX_1770278381152-e1770377456844-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/h3x-develops-modular-3d-printed-2-mw-diesel-genset-system-for-marine-and-industrial-markets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 University of Maryland’s Extensive HVAC 3D Printing Program Signals a Turning Point
Goulding and Preeti Sulibhavi highlight how the University of Maryland’s extensive HVAC 3D printing program is moving additive manufacturing from experimental concepts to real-world energy infrastructure.
The post University of Maryland’s Extensive HVAC 3D Printing Program Signals a Turning Point appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/university-of-marylands-extensive-hvac-3d-printing-program-signals-a-turning-point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Adafruit Warns of Flaws in the New Firearm Screening Bills
3D printed firearms have become a growing concern for law enforcement in recent years.
Lawmakers and online platforms have introduced new restrictions targeting both the weapons themselves and the digital files used to produce them, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 07, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/STL-Preview-of-the-Urutau.-Image-via-the-Global-Network-on-Extremism-Technology-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/adafruit-warns-of-flaws-in-the-new-firearm-screening-bills-248769&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 US Air Force Base using on-site AM lab to overcome supply chain issues
The Warner Robins Air Logistics Complex at Robins Air Force Base, Georgia, is using additive manufacturing technology to sustain legacy aircraft and overcome supply chain problems that have made the … The post US Air...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 07, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/us-air-force-base-using-on-site-am-lab-to-overcome-supply-chain-issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 FlyingBear presents FFF printer with automatic plate changer on Kickstarter
An unusual accessory for FFF 3D printers has been presented on Kickstarter: FlyingBear is promoting APS, an automatic plate changer.
The system is designed to reduce downtime, reported by 3Printr on Feb 06, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.3printr.com/flyingbear-presents-fff-printer-with-automatic-plate-changer-on-kickstarter-1286713&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Anniversary Eyewear Blends Heritage with Advanced Manufacturing
Italian eyewear and sports gear company Rudy Project is celebrating 40 years of performance eyewear with the Performance 40, a limited-edition model that combines the brand’s 1985 design DNA with modern production...
Limited to 100 units worldwide and priced at €950, the frame features a lightweight titanium structure produced using 3D printing, allowing lattice […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-06-at-13.23.14-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/anniversary-eyewear-blends-heritage-with-advanced-manufacturing-248762&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 University of Dayton Secures $450K for CFAM Roadmap to Strengthen U.S. Defense Manufacturing
National additive manufacturing accelerator America Makes, in collaboration with the National Center for Defense Manufacturing and Machining (NCDMM), announced that the University of Dayton Research Institute has...
The effort is part of the Affordable and Agile Composite Additive Manufactured Structures […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/America-Makes-facility-face-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/university-of-dayton-secures-450k-for-cfam-roadmap-to-strengthen-u-s-defense-manufacturing-248753&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Building Beneath the Waves: Cornell Advances Underwater 3D Concrete Printing
An interdisciplinary team at Cornell University is developing a method to 3D print concrete directly underwater, aiming to enable faster, lower-impact construction and repair of critical subsea infrastructure such as...
Supported by the U.S, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/0128_printing2-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/building-beneath-the-waves-cornell-advances-underwater-3d-concrete-printing-248745&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-32-2026-02-08</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #31 - 2026-02-07</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Italian hospital scaling 3D surgical planning
A urological surgery team at IRCCS Ospedale Policlinico San Martino in Genoa, Italy, has fully integrated 3D surgical planning into routine clinical practice.
Nearly 300 kidney tumor reconstruction procedures have … The post Italian hospital scaling 3D surgical planning appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/materialise-mimics-augmented-reality-3d-planning-operation-room-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/italian-hospital-scaling-3d-surgical-planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Machina Labs Secures $124 Million at a Pivotal Moment for Defense Manufacturing
Machina Labs has raised $124 million in funding.
Investors include Woven Capital, Lockheed Martin Ventures, Balerion Space Ventures, and Strategic Development Fund (SDF), reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 06, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323727/machina-labs-raises-124-million&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Barriers in Scaling and TPU Materials Limit Home Production of 3D Printed Footwear
The 3D print industry may be missing out on a major distributed application: footwear.
The post Barriers in Scaling and TPU Materials Limit Home Production of 3D Printed Footwear appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/barriers-in-scaling-and-tpu-materials-limit-home-production-of-3d-printed-footwear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Compact Pellet Extruder Enables High Content Feedstock Printing
A new research paper introduces a compact screw-based pellet extruder for high content feedstocks, and it could materially shift costs and throughput for polymer, metal and ceramic additive manufacturing.
The post Compact Pellet Extruder Enables High Content Feedstock Printing appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/compact-pellet-extruder-enables-high-content-feedstock-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Nodi releases innovative new DfAM features
Nodi, a node-based 3D modeling platform, has released a major update that introduces implicit modeling capabilities aimed at design for additive manufacturing (DfAM) workflows.
The new feature allows users to … The post Nodi releases innovative new DfAM features appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Bicycle-saddle-shape-created-with-Implicit-modeling-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nodi-releases-innovative-new-dfam-features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Slant 3D Proposes Catalog Platform as a Partial Solution to Widespread 3D Model Theft
3D model theft is rampant, and there’s not a lot that can be done.
The post Slant 3D Proposes Catalog Platform as a Partial Solution to Widespread 3D Model Theft appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/slant-3d-proposes-catalog-platform-as-a-partial-solution-to-widespread-3d-model-theft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 NASCAR turns to 3D printing to help USA Luge at the Winter Olympics
With the 2026 Winter Olympics kicking off in Italy this week, it was a surprise to no one at VoxelMatters that there would be some great 3D printing stories emerging.
… The post NASCAR turns to 3D printing to help USA Luge at the Winter Olympics appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/milano-cortina-1-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nascar-3d-printing-usa-luge-winter-olympics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Behind the Scenes of Netflix’s Stranger Things: 3D Printing in Action
3D printing is transforming visual effects by converting digital designs into tangible, highly detailed props with higher speed and precision.
For filmmakers, this allows complex scenes to be executed safely, efficiently, and with greater creative flexibility, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 06, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stranger-things-2-780x470.jpg-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/behind-the-scenes-of-netflixs-stranger-things-3d-printing-in-action-248756&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-31-2026-02-07</guid></item></channel></rss>