<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Quality3Ds Daily Pulse</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>Curated daily news for 3D printing enthusiasts.</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #46 - 2026-02-22</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Stratasys Introduces Dental Anatomical Model Preset for Education and Clinical Training
3D printer OEM Stratasys has introduced a dental anatomical model preset designed for simulation-based education and clinical training.
The multi-material 3D printed solution offers a synthetic alternative to cadavers, animal specimens, and stone models, addressing cost, variability, and ethical concerns that continue to affect traditional training, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 21, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2D1A8890-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/stratasys-introduces-dental-anatomical-model-preset-for-education-and-clinical-training-249276&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 URWAHN positions AM at forefront of Smart Bike Factory Made in Germany initiative
URWAHN Bikes, an innovative German bicycle manufacturer making 3D printed frames, has teamed up with wheelset manufacturer Roland to launch the Smart Bike Factory Made in Germany initiative.
The program … The post URWAHN positions AM at forefront of Smart Bike Factory Made in Germany initiative appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/urwahn-image-company-behind-scenes-12-e1771631835274-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/urwahn-positions-am-at-forefront-of-smart-bike-factory-made-in-germany-initiative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 3D design without learning CAD? Doodle Mode does It for you
Until recently, designing 3D models was associated with complex software and a lengthy learning curve.
A New York-based company wants to change that by introducing Doodle Mode, which turns hand-drawn … The post 3D design without learning CAD, reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 21, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/cookiecad01-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/3d-design-without-learning-cad-doodle-mode-does-it-for-you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 ATI Backs Alloyed’s 3D Printed Superalloy for Jet Engines
UK-based alloy design firm and Oxford University-spinout Alloyed has received £1 million from the UK’s Aerospace Technology Institute (ATI) Programme to help bring a new nickel superalloy closer to use in commercial...
Named ABD-1000AM, the alloy is developed for additive manufacturing, and the funding will go toward resolving one of the more stubborn […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 21, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/HoneycombTile35-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/ati-backs-alloyeds-3d-printed-superalloy-for-jet-engines-249268&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 MIT team develop multimaterial 3D printing platform to produce complex electric motors in a single step
Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have developed a multimaterial extrusion 3D printing platform designed to fabricate complete electric machines in a single manufacturing step.
Their system uses … The post MIT team develop multimaterial 3D printing platform to produce complex electric motors in a single step appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/nvpp_a_2613185_f0003_oc-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/mit-team-develop-multimaterial-3d-printing-platform-to-produce-complex-electric-motors-in-a-single-step&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Atlantic XL secures Lloyd’s Register additive manufacturing qualification
Atlantic XL Inc., a provider of EPC and EPCM services to the energy industry, claims to have become the first company in North and South America to receive Additive Manufacturing … The post Atlantic XL secures...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 20, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/XLG-01-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/atlantic-xl-secures-lloyds-register-additive-manufacturing-qualification&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Boston Scientific’s Penumbra Acquisition: Impacts and 3D Printing Opportunities in Vascular Medicine
Anthony Palumbo and Charles Goulding analyze Boston Scientific’s US$14.5 billion acquisition of Penumbra, showing how additive manufacturing can accelerate thrombectomy and neurovascular innovation through rapid...
The post Boston Scientific’s Penumbra Acquisition: Impacts and 3D Printing Opportunities in Vascular Medicine appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/boston-scientifics-penumbra-acquisition-impacts-and-3d-printing-opportunities-in-vascular-medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 This One Trick Makes Your FFF 3D Printer a Bit Safer
There’s one trick you should be doing to keep your workspace safer when 3D printing.
The post This One Trick Makes Your FFF 3D Printer a Bit Safer appeared on Fabbaloo.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/this-one-trick-makes-your-fff-3d-printer-a-bit-safer&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-46-2026-02-22</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #45 - 2026-02-21</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description /><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-45-2026-02-21</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #44 - 2026-02-20</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Stratasys introduces multi-material 3D printed anatomical model preset for dental training
"We are entering a new segment of digital dental education and clinical simulation."
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/2D1A8926.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/stratasys-introduces-multi-material-3d-printed-anatomical-model-preset-for-dental-training&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Caracol advances in-orbit autonomous LFAM for European Space Agency
Last spring, the European Space Agency (ESA) awarded large-format AM company Caracol a grant to lead the AI-Based Monitoring of Large Robotic Format Additive Manufacturing in Space (AIMIS-LFAM) project.
Now, … The post Caracol advances in-orbit autonomous LFAM for European Space Agency appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/caracol-esa-1-1-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/caracol-advances-in-orbit-autonomous-lfam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 3D printed carbon fiber meta-skins improve impact mitigation in foam-core composites
Researchers at San Diego State University’s (SDSU) Experimental Mechanics Laboratory and Advanced Manufacturing Hub have developed 3D printed continuous carbon fiber “meta-skins” designed to improve impact mitigation...
Published in Additive Manufacturing Letters, the study by Sean Eckstein, Sophia Benkirane, and George Youssef evaluates pseudo-woven composite skins fabricated using automated tow placement […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-14-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/3d-printed-carbon-fiber-meta-skins-improve-impact-mitigation-in-foam-core-composites-249193&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Axtra3D expands dental portfolio to 12 materials with new pro3dure resin and deeper Oqcam integration
Axtra3D, a leader in High-Speed SLA 3D printing, has further expanded its dental solutions portfolio to 12 validated materials with the addition of Printodent GR-19.1 OA/MSI from pro3dure.
The biomimetically … The post Axtra3D expands dental portfolio to 12 materials with new pro3dure resin and deeper Oqcam integration appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Axtra3D-Dental-Solutions-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/axtra3d-expands-dental-portfolio-to-12-materials-with-new-pro3dure-resin-and-deeper-oqcam-integration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Automation Alley's Project DIAMOnD opens up Digital Transformation Center to non-members
Small and mid-size businesses will now have access to the organisation's industrial-grade AM equipment.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/69724dff2fe8f0ffcb31729d_blog_20image-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/automation-alley-project-diamond-digital-transformation-center-non-members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Protolabs launches AI-powered ProDesk capability to provide real-time quoting and DFM analysis
ProDesk will serve clients requiring injection moulding, CNC machining and 3D printing services.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-19-at-14.17.26-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/protolabs-lau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Materialise reports stable 2025 financial results with marginal revenue increase
Materialise NV, a Belgian AM software and service provider which trades on the NASDAQ, has reported its 2025 financials, and closed the fourth quarter of the year with total revenue … The post Materialise reports...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/20170921_materialise_193-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/materialise-reports-2025-q4-revenue-growth-of-6-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Alloyed secures £1 million to develop next-gen nickel-based superalloy for 3D printing jet engine parts
The company, believes the material will be "game changing" for building gas turbines for aerospace propulsion and industrial power generation.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 19, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Alloyed-PR.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/alloyed-secures-1-million-to-develop-next-gen-nickel-based-superalloy-for-3d-printing-jet-engine-parts&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-44-2026-02-20</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #43 - 2026-02-19</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Materialise adds custom-made PEEK implants to cranio-maxillofacial portfolio
Materialise NV, a Belgium-based 3D printing software and medical device company, has introduced custom-made implants made from polyetheretherketone (PEEK) to its cranio-maxillofacial (CMF) portfolio.
Surgeons can now select either titanium or the high-performance polymer for patient-specific reconstructions while using the same digital planning and case management system, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Materialises-new-personalized-PEEK-CMF-implant-150x100.webp
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/materialise-adds-custom-made-peek-implants-to-cranio-maxillofacial-portfolio-249144&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Weaving Flexibility into Nitinol: IMDEA–UPM Advances 3D Printed Superelastic Metamaterials
Researchers from IMDEA Materials Institute and the Technical University of Madrid (UPM) have reimagined nickel-titanium (Nitinol) alloys as fabric-like, interwoven structures, achieving levels of flexibility and...
By combining design-focused approaches with advanced 3D printing, the team has created superelastic metamaterials that could transform applications in robotics, aerospace, and healthcare, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Carlos-Photos-2-2048x1365-1-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/weaving-flexibility-into-nitinol-imdea-upm-advances-3d-printed-superelastic-metamaterials-249184&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 RWTH Aachen-led AddMamBa project qualifies recycled steel for load-bearing 3D printed facade brackets
Researchers at RWTH Aachen University are investigating whether steel scrap can be transformed into certified, load-bearing construction components using 3D printing.
The BMWE-funded AddMamBa project focuses on producing optimized facade brackets from recycled steel powder via laser powder bed fusion (PBF-LB/M), aiming to reduce material consumption and improve circularity in the, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-11-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/rwth-aachen-led-addmamba-project-qualifies-recycled-steel-for-load-bearing-3d-printed-facade-brackets-249157&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ UK completes flight of 3D printed aircraft component from recycled titanium
QinetiQ, a UK defence and security technology company, has completed a flight test of an aircraft fitted with a structural component 3D printed from recycled titanium.
Flight was conducted by QinetiQ’s Flight Test Organisation at MOD Boscombe Down in Wiltshire using a company-owned Agusta A109S helicopter, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/agusta-a109-first-flight-titanium-bracket-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/uk-completes-flight-of-3d-printed-aircraft-component-from-recycled-titanium-249148&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Plastometrex launches MultiScale capability for thin-wall and high-resolution mechanical property mapping
Cambridge-based materials testing company Plastometrex has introduced a new MultiScale capability for its PLX-Benchtop system, allowing high-resolution mapping of mechanical properties across thin, welded, and...
Announced in February 2026, the update allows engineers to test specimens as thin as 0.75 mm and perform property mapping with 1.5 mm indent spacing, expanding access […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-6-150x100.jpeg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/plastometrex-launches-multiscale-capability-for-thin-wall-and-high-resolution-mechanical-property-mapping-249162&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 NASA JPL deploys AM manufactured mechanism aboard Proteus Space satellite
NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) has successfully deployed the JPL Additive Compliant Canister (JACC) in orbit, aboard the Proteus Space M1 ESPA class satellite, in a demonstration of additive manufacturing …...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Proteus-03-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nasa-jpl-deploys-am-manufactured-mechanism-aboard-proteus-space-satellite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Divergent and Mach Industries deliver UAS prototype in 71 days
Divergent Technologies and Mach Industries have collaborated on the production of a prototype autonomous strike aircraft dubbed Venom, taking the concept to a flight-ready demo in just 71 days.
The … The post Divergent and Mach Industries deliver UAS prototype in 71 days appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Divergent-Venom-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/divergent-and-mach-industries-deliver-uas-prototype-in-71-days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Plastometrex launches MultiScale capability top capture high-resolution mechanical property variation
It has been developed in a bid to address a 'common gap in mechanical testing.'
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 18, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/PLX-Benchtop-Thin-Sample.JPG
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/plastometrex-launches-multiscale-capability-top-capture-high-resolution-mechanical-property-variation&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-43-2026-02-19</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #42 - 2026-02-18</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Materialise adds custom PEEK implants to its CMF portfolio
Materialise NV, a leader in 3D printed medical devices and software, has expanded its cranio-maxillofacial (CMF) portfolio with the addition of custom-made polyetheretherketone (PEEK) implants, giving surgeons across...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/materialise-cmf-solutions-3d-printed-peek-implants-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/materialise-adds-custom-peek-implants-to-its-cmf-portfolio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Wohlers Report 2026: Additive manufacturing revenues reach $24.2 billion
The latest Wohlers Report was launched on February 17, 2026.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/AR-1098-Wohlers-2026-LI-R3.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/wohlers-report-2026-additive-manufacturing-revenues-reach-24-2-billion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Oxford University captures historic Divinity School in 3D
The University of Oxford in England is home to many historic sites, from the Baroque-style Radcliffe Camera library to the 16th century Christ Church College, which counts 13 prime ministers … The post Oxford...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/oxford-divinity-room-2-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/oxford-university-captures-historic-divinity-school-3d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ 3D printed helicopter bracket made from recycled titanium takes flight
The flight, which was conducted by QinetiQ’s Flight Test Organisation at MOD Boscombe Down in Wiltshire, is thought to be a world first.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/titanium-bracket-fitted-on-agusta-a109.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/3d-printed-helicopter-bracket-made-from-recycled-titanium-takes-flight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 IMDEA researchers develop woven nitinol to overcome 3D printing limitations
Researchers from IMDEA Materials Institute and the Technical University of Madrid (UPM) have developed a design-driven methodology that significantly increases the deformability of 3D printed nickel-titanium – or...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Foto-Carlos-Aguilar-Vega-2-scaled-e1771327947921-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/imdea-researchers-develop-woven-nitinol-to-overcome-3d-printing-limitations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 3D printing enters hotels as 358 3D printed tables are delivered to 180 apartments
Large-format 3D printing is increasingly boldly entering user industries, not only industrial ones.
One of the latest examples of such an implementation is a project by IVE LABS and Hyfer … The post 3D printing enters hotels as 358 3D printed tables are delivered to 180 apartments appeared first on VoxelMatters -...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Zrzut-ekranu-2026-02-13-120747-150x150.png
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/3d-printing-enters-hotels-as-358-tables-from-3d-printers-are-delivered-to-180-apartments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Formlabs sets sights on scaling with former Cognex CEO; Carl Bass steps down
The 3D printing company aims to tap into Rob Willett’s 30-plus years of leadership experience in industrial automation, machine vision, and global operations.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Rob-Willett.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/formlabs-sets-sights-on-scaling-with-former-cognex-ceo-carl-bass-steps-down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Formlabs IPO Speculation as Public-company Veteran Joins Board
The 3D printing group appoints former Cognex chief Rob Willett as it quietly reshapes its governance.
And starts to look a lot like a company getting ready for something, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/image-2-1-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/formlabs-ipo-speculation-as-public-company-veteran-joins-board-249104&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-42-2026-02-18</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #41 - 2026-02-17</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 MIT Introduces MagMix to Reduce Cell Settling in 3D Bioprinting, Addresses Key Limitation
Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have created MagMix, a compact magnetic system that actively prevents cell settling during 3D bioprinting, producing more uniform and functional tissues.
The innovation addresses a key limitation in biofabrication: sedimentation in bioinks—a mixture of living cells and hydrogels—which can cause clogging, uneven cell distribution, and inconsistent tissue […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/SK-01C-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/mit-introduces-magmix-to-reduce-cell-settling-in-3d-bioprinting-addresses-key-limitation-248983&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Germany Funds Titanium Aluminide Additive Reactors to Advance Hydrogen Mobility
On February 10, 2026, Matthias Hauer, German Parliamentary State Secretary at the Federal Ministry of Research, Technology and Space (BMFTR), formally handed over the funding approval for the InnoWaerm project,...
Backed with around €1.5 million through the BMFTR’s VIP+ validation […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/bild-3-pm-InnoWaerm-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/germany-funds-titanium-aluminide-additive-reactors-to-advance-hydrogen-mobility-248970&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Quickparts Introduces DuraKor, ThermaKor, and Vapour Smoothing to Bridge Prototype and Production
Quickparts, a global provider of advanced manufacturing solutions, has announced the introduction of two new high-performance plastics, DuraKor and ThermaKor, along with vapour smoothing as a standard...
These additions aim to give customers seamless support across the entire product development lifecycle, from a single prototype to large-scale production, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DuraKor_Parts_3-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/quickparts-introduces-durakor-thermakor-and-vapour-smoothing-to-bridge-prototype-and-production-248943&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Université de Lorraine team advances post-consumer mixed plastic direct processing for 3D printing
A team of researchers at the Université de Lorraine in Nancy, France, has conducted research that contributes to the development of sorting-free recycling strategies.
Working to advance the evolution of Distributed … The post Université de Lorraine team advances post-consumer mixed plastic direct processing for 3D printing appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Recycling-AM-hero-image-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/research-team-advances-post-consumer-mixed-plastic-direct-processing-for-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 35.BI-MU 2026 places robotics, digitalization and additive at the core of sustainable industry
35.BI-MU, scheduled from 13 to 16 October 2026 at fieramilano Rho, confirms its role as a key reference point for designers, production managers, buyers and system integrators evaluating investments in … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 17, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/35_Bi-MU_AMITALY__MG_9048-Copia-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/35-bi-mu-2026-places-robotics-digitalization-and-additive-at-the-core-of-sustainable-industry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 Teams Selected by ARPA-H to Develop Patient-Specific Bioprinted Organs
The Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H) has announced the first recipients of its Personalized Regenerative Immunocompetent Nanotechnology Tissue (PRINT) program.
The selected research teams from Carnegie Mellon University, Wake Forest University, the Wyss Institute, University of California San Diego, and University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center will develop advanced, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/vital-headerv2-150x100.jpg
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/teams-selected-by-arpa-h-to-develop-patient-specific-bioprinted-organs-248988&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 The Future of 3D Printing: Additive Manufacturing Expert Forecasts for 2026
3D Printing Industry asked some of the most influential people in additive manufacturing to identity the near term trends in the 3D printing industry to watch for 2026.
The annual 3DPI Executive Survey asks a cross-section of executives, technologists, service providers, and ecosystem builders to identify the near-term trends that will matter most over the […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Future-of-3D-Printing-2026-2-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/the-future-of-3d-printing-additive-manufacturing-expert-forecasts-for-2026-249050&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 Nanochon targeting $20m Series A funding round after strong start to 2026
Nanochon, an orthopedic device company developing an implant for treating articular cartilage defects in the knee, is planning a $20 million Series A funding round in Q3 of 2026, to … The post Nanochon targeting $20m...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 16, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Nanochon-hero-image-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/nanochon-targeting-20m-series-a-funding-round-after-strong-start-to-2026&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-41-2026-02-17</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #40 - 2026-02-16</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Lululemon SoHo Store Installs Large-Format 3D Printed Benches by Decibel Built
Shoppers visiting the new Lululemon flagship store in SoHo might notice something new and original when they sit down.
The benches inside the space were not carved from wood or, reported by 3DPrint.com on Feb 15, 2026.
Read more ? https://3dprint.com/323922/3d-printed-benches-bring-sustainable-design-to-lululemons-new-soho-flagship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Researchers develop a 3D printing ink that recycles with water
Researchers at the Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon’s Institute of Functional Materials for Sustainability in Teltow, Germany, have created a water-based 3D printing ink composed of approximately 70% lignin, a byproduct of...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 15, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Recycled-printing-ink-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/researchers-develop-a-3d-printing-ink-that-recycles-with-water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Fast and precise microdevice production enabled by sound-driven 3D printing
Researchers at Concordia University have developed a 3D printing technique that uses focused ultrasound to fabricate microscale structures on soft polymers, with a precision up to 10 times finer than … The post Fast...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 15, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/41378_2025_1035_Fig1_HTML-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/fast-and-precise-microdevice-production-enabled-by-sound-driven-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Chinese scientists 3D print tiny items in half a second using holographic light fields
A research team reports a holographic light-field technique that can fabricate complex millimeter-scale objects in under a second, pointing toward much faster microfabrication workflows.
Reported by Tom's Hardware.
Read more ? https://www.tomshardware.com/3d-printing/chinese-scientists-3d-print-tiny-items-in-half-a-second-using-holographic-light-fields-scientists-precision-fabricate-complex-millimeter-scale-objects-in-record-time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Make Good leverages 3D printing to offer real-world accessibility
Modern technologies, often associated with expensive gadgets and industry, are also having a growing social impact.
One example of this approach is the nonprofit organization Make Good, which uses 3D … The post Make Good leverages 3D printing to offer real-world accessibility appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MakeGood-08-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/make-good-leverages-3d-printing-to-offer-real-world-accessibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 There’s Always Room for 3D Printed Batteries
There are many applications where you have limits on how much you can cram into a particular space.
There are also many applications where you need as much battery as …read more, reported by Hackaday 3D Printing on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/pdw.png
Read more ? https://hackaday.com/2026/02/14/theres-always-room-for-3d-printed-batteries&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-40-2026-02-16</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #39 - 2026-02-15</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 Researchers develop degradation-triggered 4D printed actuators for biomedical applications
Researchers from the Universidad Politécnica de Madrid and the IMDEA Materials Institute, in collaboration with German medical technology company Meotec, have developed a degradation-triggered 4D printing method that...
Published in Additive Manufacturing, the study shows that hydrolytic degradation of polyvinyl alcohol (PVA) can be […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/image-9-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/researchers-develop-degradation-triggered-4d-printed-actuators-for-biomedical-applications-248900&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Hypersonix sets launch window for 3D printed engine-propelled hypersonic craft
Pioneering Brisbane-based aerospace startup Hypersonix Launch Systems has scheduled a late February launch window for a test flight of its DART AE, a 3.5-meter scramjet-powered hypersonic aircraft that’s designed to...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Hypersonix-01-e1770978909521-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/hypersonix-sets-launch-window-for-3d-printed-engine-propelled-hypersonic-craft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Housing Affordability, Innovation and 3D Printing
Goulding and Preeti Sulibhavi analyze how companies like Pulte, Lennar, D.R.
Horton, and KB Home are integrating additive manufacturing to cut costs and boost energy efficiency, reported by Fabbaloo on Feb 14, 2026.
Read more ? https://www.fabbaloo.com/news/housing-affordability-innovation-and-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 The 3D printed rotor guards tested, raced and won at the highest level of mountain biking
Disc brake covers have become a regular sight on the professional downhill MTB scene, and a UK-based company – G10 PRJCT – has brought the tech to the public at … The post The 3D printed rotor guards tested, raced...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSCF8760-1-e1771026458953-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/the-3d-printed-rotor-guards-tested-raced-and-won-at-the-highest-level-of-mountain-biking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Chinese team 3D print millimeter-scale objects in under one second
Researchers at Tsinghua University in Beijing have developed a 3D printing method that is able to fabricate complex millimeter-scale objects in 0.6 seconds – a feat the team has claimed … The post Chinese team 3D...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 14, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DISH-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/chinese-team-3d-print-millimeter-scale-objects-in-under-one-second
Read more (Tom's Hardware) ? https://www.tomshardware.com/3d-printing/chinese-scientists-3d-print-tiny-items-in-half-a-second-using-holographic-light-fields-scientists-precision-fabricate-complex-millimeter-scale-objects-in-record-time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 Thingiverse Joins MyMiniFactory in Major 3D Printing Community Consolidation
MyMiniFactory, a curated 3D printing community where independent designers and brands sell digital models, has completed the full acquisition of Thingiverse from Netherlands-based 3D printer manufacturer Ultimaker.
The move brings over eight million users into MyMiniFactory’s ecosystem and incorporates Thingiverse into its SoulCrafted platform, which emphasizes human-created designs, curated collections, and sustainable, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/019c4cb5-826f-70bf-9bff-4bd98ac52b36-cover-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/thingiverse-joins-myminifactory-in-major-3d-printing-community-consolidation-248924&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Dutch additive manufacturing software group Dimanex declared bankrupt
Small but influential digital supply chain startup collapses amid tightening capital and slower enterprise adoption A Dutch software company that sought to transform industrial supply chains through additive...
Dimanex B.V., a Utrecht-based developer of […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCI-MacBook-Frame-1-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/dutch-additive-manufacturing-software-group-dimanex-declared-bankrupt-248922&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 3DPI Executive Survey 2026: The Future of 3D Printing and The Year of Institutional Filters
The additive manufacturing industry has spent two decades arguing about what’s possible.
In 2026, the conversation has finally shifted to what’s survivable, reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/State-of-Investment-Series-1-1-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/3dpi-executive-survey-2026-the-future-of-3d-printing-and-the-year-of-institutional-filters-248919&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-39-2026-02-15</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #38 - 2026-02-14</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 MIT researchers give further insight into 3D bioprinting mixer
Researchers at MIT who developed a magnetic mixing device that solves a fundamental challenge in 3D bioprinting have spoken about MagMix and its potential future impact on regenerative medicine.
The … The post MIT researchers give further insight into 3D bioprinting mixer appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MagMix-01-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/mit-researchers-give-further-insight-into-3d-bioprinting-mixer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 Exploring additive manufacturing in the 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations
The newly released 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations introduce significant updates concerning additive manufacturing (AM), reflecting the evolving role of this technology in motorsport engineering.
These regulations establish the materials, … The post Exploring additive manufacturing in the 2026 Formula 1 Technical Regulations appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of additive manufacturing.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/FIA-2026-Formula-1-regulations-3-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/exploring-additive-manufacturing-in-the-2026-formula-1-technical-regulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Japan's first government-approved two-story 3D printed reinforced concrete house completed
The 537-square-foot house is said to meet Japan’s stringent seismic design requirements.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/image--12--1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/japans-first-government-approved-two-story-3d-printed-reinforced-concrete-house-completed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ AM Solutions introduces upgraded M1 surface finishing system for 3D printed metal &amp;amp; polymer parts
The new M1 combines smoothing, grinding, polishing, and deburring in a single vibratory finishing platform.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/M1--1--1.jpg
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/am-solutions-m1-surface-finishing-metal-polymer-parts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 Five use cases that show the life-changing impact of medical 3D printing
This month, our AM Focus is shining a light on the medical sector, where additive manufacturing technologies have not only been broadly adopted but have gained notable mainstream attention (admittedly … The post Five...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/osorio-spinal-implant-02-082825-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/five-use-cases-that-show-the-life-changing-impact-of-medical-3d-printing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦺 PrintBio joins federal kidney bioprinting program
PrintBio, a New York City-based regenerative medicine and bioprinting company, has joined a multidisciplinary research consortium that’s being funded by the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H) – a …...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/PrintBio-01-150x150.jpeg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/printbio-joins-federal-kidney-bioprinting-program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📰 Leitat and DISCMAM help shape AM Village 2026 program across Madrid and Albacete
Leitat Technological Center joined the second preparation meeting for AM Village 2026 in Madrid, represented by Xavier Tutó, where organizers refined the technical and operational plan for the five-day workshop … The...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/WAAM3D_AM-VILLAGE-2026-Meeting-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/leitat-and-discmam-help-shape-am-village-2026-program-across-madrid-and-albacete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 [INTERVIEW] Thingiverse Reboot Targets Creator Pay Tools and Tighter AI Controls after MyMiniFactory Acquisition
Thingiverse, one of the oldest and most visited libraries of downloadable 3D-print files, is being repositioned around creator monetisation, human-led curation and stricter handling of AI-generated uploads after its...
Romain Kidd, the newly appointed chief executive of Thingiverse and former MMF CEO, said the platform remains large by any consumer internet […], reported by 3D Printing Industry on Feb 13, 2026.
Image ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/019c4cb5-826f-70bf-9bff-4bd98ac52b36-cover-150x100.png
Read more ? https://3dprintingindustry.com/news/interview-thingiverse-reboot-targets-creator-pay-tools-and-tighter-ai-controls-after-myminifactory-acquisition-248928&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-38-2026-02-14</guid></item><item><title>3D PRINTING PULSE #37 - 2026-02-13</title><link>https://quality3ds.godaddysites.com</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🦺 restor3d launches Ossera AFX ankle fusion cage system
restor3d, a global leader in patient-specific, 3D printed, musculoskeletal implants, has launched its Ossera AFX Ankle Fusion Cage System for full commercial distribution, in an expansion of the platform that … The...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ossera-AFX-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/restor3d-launches-ossera-afx-ankle-fusion-cage-system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚀 British aerospace firm Orbex set to enter administration
The Exploration Company is among those to have explored an acquisition of the company.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/380A1599_2022-05-27-131523_hkda-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/orbex-set-to-enter-administration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Two-story 3D printed home passes Japan’s stringent seismic standards
As a country that experiences upwards of 500,000 earthquakes every year, Japan is correct to have highly stringent building requirements.
These requirements—the New Anti-seismic Structure Standard from 1981 in particular— … The post Two-story 3D printed home passes Japan’s stringent seismic standards appeared first on VoxelMatters - The heart of...
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/cobod-japan-1-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/two-story-3d-printed-home-seismic-approval-japan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♻️ Application spotlight: 100-micron 3D printed veneers enable reduction in teeth grinding for patients
BMF believes it is the world's thinnest veneer product.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/01/image-61-1.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/application-spotlight-100-micron-3d-printed-veneers-enable-reduction-in-teeth-grinding-for-patients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🖨 MyMiniFactory acquires Thingiverse from Ultimaker
MyMiniFactory has acquired 100% of Thingiverse from Ultimaker, bringing together nearly 8 million users under a single platform that has paid out over $100 million to independent creators since its … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/MyMiniFactory-Thingiverse-merger-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/myminifactory-acquires-thingiverse-from-ultimaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 ARKKY’s next-gen 3D printed shoes blend design, innovation, and sustainability
ARKKY is a young footwear brand with a modern approach to fashion.
The company emphasizes that it does not follow patterns or trends but sets them itself, reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ARKKY-01-150x150.webp
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/arkkys-next-gen-3d-printed-shoes-blend-design-innovation-and-sustainability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏠 Researchers investigate turning construction waste into metal 3D printing feedstock
BMWE-funded research project explores if CO₂ emissions from construction sector could be significantly reduced using recycled steel to build reusable 3D printed facade brackets.
Reported by TCT Magazine on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/content/images/2026/02/Image1_AddMamba-scaled.png
Read more ? https://www.tctmagazine.com/researchers-investigate-turning-construction-waste-into-metal-3d-printing-feedstock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 Ceramitec puts additive manufacturing of technical ceramics on center stage
The conference program at the Ceramitec 2026 trade fair in Munich, from March 24 to 26, will foreground additive manufacturing, with multiple sessions on 3D printed technical ceramics and digitally … The post...
Reported by VoxelMatters on Feb 12, 2026.
Image ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ceramitec-Konferenzprogramm-150x150.jpg
Read more ? https://www.voxelmatters.com/ceramitec-puts-additive-manufacturing-of-technical-ceramics-on-center-stage&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>pulse-37-2026-02-13</guid></item></channel></rss>